<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<root>
<name>open()</name>

<category>Input</category>

<subcategory>Files</subcategory>

<usage>Application</usage>

<example>
<image></image>
<code>
void setup() {
  size(200, 200);
}

void draw() { 
  // draw() must be present for mousePressed() to work
}

void mousePressed() {
  println("Opening Process_4");
  open("/Applications/Process_4.app");
}

</code>
</example>


<example>
<image></image>
<code>
void setup() {
  size(200, 200);
}

void draw() { 
  // draw() must be present for mousePressed() to work
}

void mousePressed() {
  String[] params = { "/usr/bin/jikes", "-help" };
  open(params);
}

</code>
</example>

<description>
Attempts to open an application or file using your platform's launcher. The <b>file</b> parameter is a String specifying the file name and location. The location parameter must be a full path name, or the name of an executable in the system's PATH. In most cases, using a full path is the best option, rather than relying on the system PATH. Be sure to make the file executable before attempting to open it (chmod +x). 
<br/> <br/>
The <b>args</b> parameter is a String or String array which is passed to the command line. If you have multiple parameters, e.g. an application and a document, or a command with multiple switches, use the version that takes a String array, and place each individual item in a separate element. 
<br/> <br/>
If args is a String (not an array), then it can only be a single file or application with no parameters. It's not the same as executing that String using a shell. For instance, open("jikes -help") will not work properly.
<br/> <br/>
This function behaves differently on each platform. On Windows, the parameters are sent to the Windows shell via "cmd /c". On Mac OS X, the "open" command is used (type "man open" in Terminal.app for documentation). On Linux, it first tries gnome-open, then kde-open, but if neither are available, it sends the command to the shell without any alterations. 
<br/> <br/>
For users familiar with Java, this is not quite the same as Runtime.exec(), because the launcher command is prepended. Instead, the <b>exec(String[])</b> function is a shortcut for Runtime.getRuntime.exec(String[]). 
</description>

<syntax>
open(<c>file</c>)
open(<c>args</c>)
</syntax>

<parameter>
<label>file</label>
<description>String: name of the file</description>
</parameter>

<parameter>
<label>args</label>
<description>String[]: list of commands passed to the command line</description>
</parameter>

<returns>None or Process</returns>

<related></related>

<availability>1.0</availability>

<type>function</type>

<partof>Core</partof>

<level>Extended</level>

</root>
