<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<root>
<name>loadImage()</name>

<category>Image</category>

<subcategory>Loading &amp; Displaying</subcategory>

<usage>Web &amp; Application</usage>

<example>
<image>loadImage_.jpg</image>
<code><![CDATA[
PImage b;
b = loadImage("laDefense.jpg");
image(b, 0, 0);
]]></code>
</example>

<example>
<image>loadImage_.jpg</image>
<code><![CDATA[
// Loading an image when using setup() and draw()

PImage b;

void setup() {
  b = loadImage("laDefense.jpg");
  noLoop();
}

void draw() {
  image(b, 0, 0);
}
]]></code>
</example>


<example>
<code><![CDATA[
PImage online;

void setup() {
  String url = "http://processing.org/img/processing_beta_cover.gif";
  online = loadImage(url, "png");
  noLoop();
}

void draw() {
  image(online, 0, 0);
}
]]></code>
</example>


<description><![CDATA[
Loads an image into a variable of type <b>PImage</b>. Four types of images ( <b>.gif</b>, <b>.jpg</b>, <b>.tga</b>, <b>.png</b>) images may be loaded. To load correctly, images must be located in the data directory of the current sketch. In most cases, load all images in <b>setup()</b> to preload them at the start of the program. Loading images inside <b>draw()</b> will reduce the speed of a program. 
<br/> <br/>
The <b>filename</b> parameter can also be a URL to a file found online. For security reasons, a Processing sketch found online can only download files from the same server from which it came. Getting around this restriction requires a <A HREF="http://processing.org/hacks/doku.php?id=hacks:signapplet">signed applet</A>.
<br/> <br/>
The <b>extension</b> parameter is used to determine the image type in cases where the image filename does not end with a proper extension. Specify the extension as the second parameter to <b>loadImage()</b>, as shown in the third example on this page.
<br/> <br/>
If an image is not loaded successfully, the <b>null</b> value is returned and an error message will be printed to the console. The error message does not halt the program, however the null value may cause a NullPointerException if your code does not check whether the value returned from <b>loadImage()</b> is null.
<br/> <br/>
Depending on the type of error, a <b>PImage</b> object may still be returned, but the width and height of the image will be set to -1. This happens if bad image data is returned or cannot be decoded properly. Sometimes this happens with image URLs that produce a 403 error or that redirect to a password prompt, because <b>loadImage()</b> will attempt to interpret the HTML as image data.
]]></description>

<syntax><![CDATA[
loadImage(<kbd>filename</kbd>)
loadImage(<kbd>filename</kbd>, <kbd>extension</kbd>)
]]></syntax>

<parameter>
<label>filename</label>
<description><![CDATA[String: name of file to load, can be .gif, .jpg, .tga, or a handful of other image types depending on your platform.]]></description>
</parameter>

<parameter>
<label>extension</label>
<description><![CDATA[String: the type of image to load, for example "png", "gif", "jpg"]]></description>
</parameter>

<returns>PImage or null</returns>

<related>
PImage 
image() 
imageMode() 
background() 
</related>

<availability>1.0</availability>

<type>Function</type>

<partof>Core</partof>








</root>
