<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<root>

<name>PRequest</name>

<category>
Net
</category>

<subcategory>
</subcategory>

<description>
The <b>PRequest</b> object represents an active network request. They are
returned by the methods in the <b>PClient</b> used to initiate network
requests.  A request object can be in one of the states specified by the
constant values below.  As the state of the request changes, library
events are fired to notify the sketch.
</description>

<field>
  <fname>STATE_OPENED</fname>
  <fdescription>Constant value representing that the request is being sent to the server, waiting for reply</fdescription>
</field>
<field>
  <fname>STATE_CONNECTED</fname>
  <fdescription>Constant value representing that the request has been received and a response is available.</fdescription>
</field>
<field>
  <fname>STATE_FETCHING</fname>
  <fdescription>Constant value representing that the response is being fetched from the server.</fdescription>
</field>
<field>
  <fname>STATE_DONE</fname>
  <fdescription>Constant value representing that the entire response has been read.</fdescription>
</field>
<field>
  <fname>STATE_ERROR</fname>
  <fdescription>Constant value representing that an error occurred and the connection has been closed.</fdescription>
</field>
<field>
  <fname>STATE_CLOSED</fname>
  <fdescription>Constant value representing that connection has been closed and resources have been released.</fdescription>
</field>
<field>
  <fname>EVENT_CONNECTED</fname>
  <fdescription>Event fired when the server has received the request and a response is available.</fdescription>
</field>
<field>
  <fname>EVENT_DONE</fname>
  <fdescription>Event fired when the entire response has been read and is available.</fdescription>
</field>
<field>
  <fname>EVENT_ERROR</fname>
  <fdescription>Event fired when an error has occurred.</fdescription>
</field>
<field>
  <fname>state</fname>
  <fdescription>The current state of the connection, as specified by the above constants</fdescription>
</field>

<method>
  <mname>read()</mname>
  <mdescription>Reads the next byte of data and returns it as an int.</mdescription>
</method>
<method>
  <mname>readChar()</mname>
  <mdescription>Reads the next byte of data and returns it as a char.</mdescription>
</method>
<method>
  <mname>readBytes()</mname>
  <mdescription>Reads the rest of the response from the server.</mdescription>
</method>
<method>
  <mname>close()</mname>
  <mdescription>Closes the connection and releases the resources associated with this request to the server.</mdescription>
</method>

<constructor>
</constructor>


<related>
PClient
</related>

</root>
