<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<courses>
    <course>
        <date>1st August, 2008</date>
        <institution>Bioinformatics Centre, Pune University</institution>
        <title>Computer Graphics and Visualization for Computational Biologists</title>
        <description>This is a 6 months long regular module for Masters students (Masters in Bioinformatics@Pune University) intended to expertise students ability for data modeling using computer graphics concepts. This course uses Processing and R (statistical software) for the practical sessions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;*Introduction to computer graphics. &lt;br /&gt;*Data interpretation through visualization. *Object Oriented programming in Java. &lt;br /&gt;*Image processing and interactive visualization through processing. &lt;br /&gt;*Advance plotting using R.&lt;br /&gt;* Application of computer graphics and visualization in Bioinformatics.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Ranjib Dey</name>
            <email>ranjib_dey at persistent dot co dot in</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title></title>
                <url></url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title></title>
                <url></url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title></title>
                <url></url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title></title>
                <url></url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title></title>
                <url></url>
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>21,28 y 5 de julio</date>
        <institution>Museo Nacional de Artes Visuales, Montevideo-Uruguay</institution>
        <title>Taller Introducción a Processing</title>
        <description>Ciclo arte+código. &lt;br /&gt;Taller Introducción a Processing&lt;br /&gt;Enrique Aguerre y Tomás Laurenzo&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;El taller está dirigido a artistas visuales, diseñadores, músicos, arquitectos y a todas aquellas personas interesadas en la programación como medio creativo.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;El objetivo del taller consiste en brindar a los asistentes conocimientos básicos de programación orientada al desarrollo de proyectos audiovisuales.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Museo Nacional de Artes Visuales&lt;br /&gt;Montevideo, Uruguay&lt;br /&gt;</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Enrique Aguerre</name>
            <email>enriqueaguerre at gmail dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Museo Nacional de Artes Visuales</title>
                <url>http://www.manv.gub.uy/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>21, 28 de junio y 5 de julio</date>
        <institution>Museo Nacional de Artes Visuales</institution>
        <title>Ciclo arte+código. Taller Introducción a Processing</title>
        <description>El taller está dirigido a artistas visuales, diseñadores, músicos, arquitectos y a todas aquellas personas interesadas en la programación como medio creativo.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Processing es un lenguaje y entorno de programación de código libre basado en Java, que fue desarrollado por Casey Reas y Ben Fry en el Grupo de Investigación de Computación Estética del MIT Media Lab (Massachusetts Institute of Technology).&lt;br /&gt;www.processing.org&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;El objetivo del taller consiste en brindar a los asistentes conocimientos básicos de programación orientada al desarrollo de proyectos audiovisuales.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Contenidos&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[primer día]&lt;br /&gt;Definición arte+código &lt;br /&gt;Cronología de arte y tecnología. &lt;br /&gt;Programación cero. &lt;br /&gt;Proyectos realizados en Processing &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[segundo día]&lt;br /&gt;Processing [sitio web &amp; comunidad] &lt;br /&gt;Instalación del programa. &lt;br /&gt;Primeras líneas e instrucciones. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[tercer día] Conceptos de programación:&lt;br /&gt;Métodos | Variables &lt;br /&gt;If | Bucles &lt;br /&gt;Arrays | Funciones | Clases &lt;br /&gt;Tipografía | Sonido | Video &lt;br /&gt;Bibliotecas externas &lt;br /&gt;Exportar la aplicación &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Las inscripciones son libres y gratuitas y el cupo es limitado. Inscripciones previas: educativamnav@gmail.com&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Se recomienda la asistencia al taller con computadora portátil en caso de poseerla. Se entregará certificado por el 100% de asistencia</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Museo Nacional de Artes Visuales</name>
            <email>educativamnav at gmail dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Monday, June 9th 2008</date>
        <institution>Flashbelt Conference - Minneapolis, MN</institution>
        <title>Learning Processing</title>
        <description>This two-hour presentation will cover both basic and intermediate Processing topics. Hour One will focus on getting started with Processing and programming basic interactivity. Hour Two will introduce options for integrating Processing with more traditional applications. Raster, vector, text, Quicktime and 3-D output will be covered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&quot;The annual Flashbelt conference brings a few hundred designers and developers together in Minneapolis to get their geek on.  Attendees mix, mingle and learn from a cadre of rock-star designers, whiz-kid developers, and best-selling authors.  These industry leaders give presentations and lead workshops on an array of timely technology topics.  They teach tangible skills, inspire by example and answer lots of questions from attendees.  As you might have guessed most of these topics revolve around Adobe Flash and related technologies.&quot;</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Tim Armato</name>
            <email>tim at armatodesign dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Flashbelt</title>
                <url>http://flashbelt.com/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>p{three-sixty}5</title>
                <url>http://p365.armatodesign.com/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>23,24 Mayo</date>
        <institution>niu , espacio artístico contemporáneo. (Barcelona. Spain)</institution>
        <title>PROCESSING:  Introducción</title>
        <description>Primeros pasos en Processing. El lenguaje de los esbozos electrónicos.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Este curso de iniciación servirá para tener el primer contacto con la herramienta, para conocer trabajos actuales en los que se esté utilizando y empezar a escribir las primeras lineas de código.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Alba G. Corral</name>
            <email>alba at albagcorral dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>niu</title>
                <url>http://www.niubcn.com/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>albagcorral.com</title>
                <url>http://www.albagcorral.com/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 08</date>
        <institution>UDK Berlin</institution>
        <title>Digital Fabrication</title>
        <description>Digital technologies like rapid prototyping, laser cutting and CNC milling help to change industrial production processes from mass production to mass customization and manufacturing-on-demand. Using this technolgies code-based design strategies can now be extended to physical form and allow to leave the limitations of virtual space.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The course will teach the technical basics for the computational production of physical Objects. It will examine new strategies of creating unique design in form and function using parameterized processes and modularized structures.&lt;br /&gt;</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Christian Riekoff</name>
            <email>info at texone dot org</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>gestalten mit code</title>
                <url>http://entropie.digital.udk-berlin.de/wiki/GestaltenMitCode</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>digital fabrication</title>
                <url>http://entropie.digital.udk-berlin.de/wiki/Digital_fabrication</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fecha inicio: 30 de Abril 2008</date>
        <institution>IUNA Multimedia - Argentina -</institution>
        <title>Processing: programación para el arte interactivo. Net.Art e instalaciones interactivas con nuevas tecnologías.</title>
        <description>El objetivo de este curso es capacitar al alumno en la programación con fines artísticos, de forma que este pueda realizar trabajos de Net.Art, con interfaces físicas y de arte interactivo en general. Con tal fin, la meta es enseñar al alumno el lenguaje de programación Processing, el cual fue diseñado para contemplar las necesidades de los artistas relacionados con las nuevas tecnologías.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Emiliano Causa</name>
            <email>e_causa at yahoo dot com dot ar</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Curso Processing</title>
                <url>http://iuna.edu.ar/departamentos/multimedia/investiga/cursos/2008-post-processing.htm</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>IUNA Multimedia</title>
                <url>http://multimedia.iuna.edu.ar/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Tutorial del Curso</title>
                <url>http://www.biopus.com.ar/emiliano/tutorial_programacion/index.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>3-5 April 2008</date>
        <institution>Alberta College of Art + Design</institution>
        <title>Processing Workshop</title>
        <description>Variables. Functions. Ifs. Loops. Arrays. Classes. All in 3 days.

Day 1: Through short lectures and practical exercises, the workshop will cover programming fundamentals while keeping a footing in aesthetic explorations.
Day 2: Participants will build their own projects to appropriate the material first hand.
Day 3: We will push the limits and step outside the programming box, towards a more generalized understanding of the stakes and possibilities code offers.

Come with ideas.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Elie Zananiri</name>
            <email>ez at silentlycrashing dot net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Workshop notes</title>
                <url>http://www.silentlycrashing.net/p5/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>ACAD</title>
                <url>http://www.acad.ab.ca/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 08</date>
        <institution>Sabanci University, Istanbul</institution>
        <title>VA546 - Sound Projects</title>
        <description>Surround mixing, Midi technologies, Microphone techniques, Studio Recording, ,Creating Audio-Visual Interactive Environments will be the focus of this course. It will involve the selection and use of prerecorded material, as well as the creation of music and audio content. This course deals with learning how to use Max/MSP/Jitter and Processing to create interactive environments with physical computing methods.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Selcuk ARTUT</name>
            <email>sartut at sabanciuniv dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>course website</title>
                <url>http://people.sabanciuniv.edu/~sartut/courses/va546.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>14 of January 2008 - 10 of May 2008</date>
        <institution>Universidad Icesi - Cali - Colombia</institution>
        <title>Fundamentos de programación para el diseño</title>
        <description>Fundamental course of programming for designers using Procesing.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Juan Carlos Muñoz</name>
            <email>jcmunoz at gmail dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Programa del curso</title>
                <url>http://stan.desarrollo.icesi.edu.co/pls/portal/psiaepre.pprecon_contactual?pdescripmat_codigo=09686</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Diseño de medios interactivos</title>
                <url>http://www.icesi.edu.co/dmi/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Universidad Icesi</title>
                <url>http://www.icesi.edu.co/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Del 12 de febrero al 13 de marzo del 2008</date>
        <institution>Centro Multimedia, CENART, Mexico</institution>
        <title>Libre y Abierto: Taller de software y hardware libre</title>
        <description>El propósito del curso es explorar el uso de plataformas de código abierto (open source) para la creación artística. Para ello aprenderemos a instalar el sistema operativo Linux, los principios de la programación de gráficas con el software Processing y los principios de la electrónica y programación de microcontroladores con la plataforma Arduino. Así, revisaremos técnicas para integrar y usar estas aplicaciones de modo conjunto. El curso se enfocará en realizar una serie de ejercicios y experimentos orientados a la creación de interactivos, instalaciones, performance y otras formas artísticas.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Jaime Villarreal</name>
            <email>jesusjaime at gmail dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Libre y Abierto</title>
                <url>http://cmm.cenart.gob.mx/cartelera/cursos.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>February 2008</date>
        <institution>Master Multimedia - University of Florence, Italy</institution>
        <title>Fundamentals of Digital Media and Programming</title>
        <description>The course presents the fundamentals of digital audio, images, video and 3D. &lt;br /&gt;Students with various background, mostly creative, learn how to realize Processing programs that generate and manipulate such media. Several examples and exercises of increasing complexity are presented throughout the course, together with the most influent creative works of software art of the past and present.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Walter Nunziati</name>
            <email>nunziati at dsi dot unifi dot it</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Master Multimedia</title>
                <url>http://www.mmm.unifi.it/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Pietro Pala</title>
                <url>http://viplab.dsi.unifi.it/~pala/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Walter Nunziati</title>
                <url>http://viplab.dsi.unifi.it/~nunziati</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2008 (beginning 1/14/2008)</date>
        <institution>North Lake College (Irving, TX)</institution>
        <title>Programming for Artists</title>
        <description>Are you creative or artistic but afraid of learning a computer programming language? Learn to use Processing (processing.org) and Java to create computer programs that explore the elements and principles of design - color, space, line, etc. Finished web application will resemble modern art.  Online semester-length credit class.  No previous programming experience required.  (ITSE 1411.7428 Programming for Artists)</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Sharon Huston</name>
            <email>sharonhuston at dcccd dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Sample Class Calendar</title>
                <url>http://nlecommerce1.dcccd.edu/instructors/richard/classes/p4a/calendar.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>NLC Home Page</title>
                <url>http://www.northlakecollege.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>4-5 February 2008</date>
        <institution>?stanbul Bilgi University, Department of Visual Communication Design</institution>
        <title>Designing with Code</title>
        <description>The goal of this workshop is to learn fundamentals of computer programming in the context of the image/video processing. In this case, Undergraduate students will explore computational concepts in print. We will use the Proce55ing programming language to practice the discussed concepts. Previous programming experience is not required.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Mustafa Ercan Z?rh</name>
            <email>mezirh at bilgi dot edu dot tr</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2007</date>
        <institution>Georgia Tech</institution>
        <title>The Computer as an Expressive Medium</title>
        <description>The goal of this course is to learn Java programming in the context of an art and design practice, that is, to understand computation as an expressive medium. We juxtapose reading and discussion of seminal articles in computational media with Java programming projects designed to exercise specific technical skills as well as encourage conceptual explorations in computational art and design.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Ali Mazalek</name>
            <email>mazalek at gatech dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Coure Webpage</title>
                <url>http://dm.lcc.gatech.edu/~mazalek/courses/fall07/lcc6310/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Georgia Tech Digital Media Program</title>
                <url>http://dm.lcc.gatech.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2008</date>
        <institution>University of Advancing Technology</institution>
        <title>Introduction to Processing</title>
        <description>Processing is an open source programming language and environment for people who want to program images, animation and sound. It is used by students, artists, designers, architects, researchers and hobbyists for learning, prototyping and production. It is created to teach fundamentals of computer programming within a visual context and to serve as a software sketchbook and professional production tool. Processing is developed by artists and designers as an alternative to proprietary software tools in the same domain. Mobile Processing is a programming environment and library for writing software for mobile phones.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Todd Spencer</name>
            <email>tspencer at uat dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>University of Advancing Technology</title>
                <url>http://www.uat.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Robotics and Embedded Systems</title>
                <url>http://www.uat.edu/majors/robotics_and_embedded_systems.aspx</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Artificial Life Programming</title>
                <url>http://www.uat.edu/majors/a-life_programming.aspx</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Digital Art and Design</title>
                <url>http://www.uat.edu/majors/digital_art_and_design.aspx</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2008</date>
        <institution>Royal College of Art, MA Design Interactions</institution>
        <title>Processing</title>
        <description>Processing will be utilised as an introduction to computer programming for students from diverse creative backgrounds. The workshop will explore various aspects of the platform, including imagery, sound, animation, networking, data visualisation, mobile devices and physical computing. It also discusses both historical and contemporary examples of computer usage in art and design and encourages a critical approach towards conceptual aspects of the field.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>David Muth</name>
            <email>david at test dot at</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Royal College of Art</title>
                <url>http://www.rca.ac.uk/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>MA Design Interactions</title>
                <url>http://www.interaction.rca.ac.uk/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>David Muth</title>
                <url>http://www.davidmuth.net/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>26-27 October 2007</date>
        <institution>Stetson University, Deland, Florida</institution>
        <title>physical gaming workshop using computer vision</title>
        <description>This workshop will give participants an opportunity to design their own games using a camera as an input device. It will introduce them to both physical computing using computer vision techniques and game design. Each participant will have the opportunity to work with sample computer vision algorithms. All games will be written in the Processing programming language.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>andrew hieronymi</name>
            <email>andrew at rhizome dot org</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>workshop documentation</title>
                <url>http://ahieronymi.net/workshops/stetson/index.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Oct 2007 - Jan 2008</date>
        <institution>Institut Medienkunst, FHNW, Aarau, Switzerland</institution>
        <title>Grundkurs Processing</title>
        <description>Processing wurde als Programmiersprache speziell für Gestalter und Künstler entwickelt. Sie eignet sich speziell für die Programmierung von Bildern, Animation und Sound und führt sehr schnell zu visuell ansprechenden Resultaten. Durch den einfachen Aufbau mit einem einzigen Editierfenster wird einen klarer Blick auf das Grundwesen des Programmierens ermöglicht. &lt;br /&gt;Im Grundkurs von Andres Wanner geht es um ein Verständnis der elementaren Strukturen, die für das Programmieren notwendig sind.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Inhalte:&lt;br /&gt;- Programmieren von Grund auf verstehen lernen&lt;br /&gt;- effizient und strukturiert programmieren  &lt;br /&gt;- Variablen und Datentypen &lt;br /&gt;- Arrays und Schleifen &lt;br /&gt;- Modularisieren mit Functions</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Andres Wanner</name>
            <email>andres dot wanner at fhnw dot ch</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Institut Medienkunst, FHNW</title>
                <url>http://www.medienkunst.ch/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Processing-Kurspage</title>
                <url>http://www.pixelstorm.ch/processing/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>October 1st to December 7th 2007</date>
        <institution>Latin-American Institute of Communication Technology</institution>
        <title>Tut, tut, tut: yo ordeno, tú dibujas</title>
        <description>This is an online Processing course in Spanish. Anyone can enroll, but it was specially designed for teenagers studying in public schools in Mexico. It is being implemented at the national School-Web (Red Escolar) project of Mexico&apos;s Ministry of Education. At present 3938 students in 566 different public schools from all over the country are taking the course.&lt;br /&gt;</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Annabel Castro</name>
            <email>annabel dot castro at gmail dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Tut, tut, tut: yo ordeno, tú dibujas</title>
                <url>http://redescolar.ilce.edu.mx/redescolar/proyectos/tut_oto07/index.htm#</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Winter 2008</date>
        <institution>Concordia University</institution>
        <title>The Languages of Programming</title>
        <description>An introduction to programming with a strong emphasis on new media art practices.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The theoretical part of the course will outline the evolution of computing and its cultural implications, and will highlight various possibilities for integrating programming into multimedia projects and installations. While gaining a deeper understanding of computing in general, students will acquire knowledge of the basic object-oriented programming techniques, and will apply these using the Processing language. Processing is a derivative of the Java object-oriented language which is created by/for artists and designers. As such, it will enable the students to focus directly on graphical and interactive applications.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The course will consist of lectures, readings, discussions, in-class exercises and bi-weekly assignments. About ten practical exercises, addressing particular programming concepts, and one or two theory questions will constitute an assignment. Certain practical exercises will be straightforward while others will leave room for creativity.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Elie Zananiri</name>
            <email>ez at silentlycrashing dot net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>CART 253</title>
                <url>http://hybrid.concordia.ca/~cart253/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Computation Arts</title>
                <url>http://computationarts.concordia.ca/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Concordia University</title>
                <url>http://concordia.ca/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2008</date>
        <institution>L&apos;école supérieure d&apos;art d&apos;Aix-en-Provence</institution>
        <title>Objets orientés-objet</title>
        <description>Depuis plusieurs années, L&apos;atelier hypermédia réfléchit sur les rapports entre art + code en explorant les concepts et idéologies sous-jacants dans les nouveaux materiaux algorithmiques. Parallèlement, l&apos;atelier assure une veille technologique avec ses mêmes matières mais de façon totalement pragmatique en suivant le principe de « Just-Fuck-Around® ». Quelque part entre ces deux pratiques -- analytique d&apos;une côté et joyeusement bordellique de l&apos;autre -- l&apos;atelier dispense un savoir-faire technique rigoureuse. Le but de ce seminaire est d&apos;approfondir cette approche en se donnant les moyens d&apos;explorer des outils et techniques les plus avancés de la programmation. Le but, comme toujours, sera de former des artistes sachant utiliser la modularité des ordinateurs à leur avantage en inventant leurs propres dispositifs artistiques et médiatiques (c&apos;est-à-dire leurs propres média, d&apos;où le terme « hypermédia »). De ce point de vue, le seminaire s&apos;appuyera sur les travaux de ses participants, où nous chercherons à identifier les différentes stratégies possibles de la programmation, tout en identifiant les outils et logiques récurrentes entre les divers projets.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Douglas Edric Stanley</name>
            <email>douglas at abstractmachine dot net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>objets-orientés objet</title>
                <url>http://www.ecole-art-aix.fr/article2548.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Atelier hypermédia</title>
                <url>http://www.ecole-art-aix.fr/rubrique11.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>L&apos;école supérieure d&apos;art d&apos;Aix-en-Provence</title>
                <url>http://www.ecole-art-aix.fr/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>abstractmachine</title>
                <url>http://www.abstractmachine.net/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Autumn 2007</date>
        <institution>L&apos;école supérieure d&apos;art d&apos;Aix-en-Provence</institution>
        <title>Objets orientés-image</title>
        <description>- Année : 2007-2008
- Intitulé : « Objets orientés-image : Introduction à la programmation avec Processing »
- Enseignant (s) : Douglas Edric Stanley (http://www.abstractmachine.net]
- Date et heure : 10 x Jeudi matin, de 9h30 à 12h30, Semestre 1

Objectifs
- Découvrir les possibilités de l&apos;algorithme dans la création de dispositifs artistiques
- Bien connaître l&apos;environement de programmation « Processing »
- Acquisition des techniques de base permettant de gérer seul ou à plusieurs un projet d&apos;œuvre interactive ou évolutive

Contenu
L&apos;objet classique, qu&apos;il soit fabriqué de façon artisanal ou en série, est désormé hanté par une toute nouvelle catégorie d&apos;objet : celle des objets de programmation. L&apos; « objet » en programmation s&apos;empare de plus en plus des objets matériels, introduisant en ceux-ci des logiques d&apos;abstraction, de modularité, de communications hybrides, de collectivation des savoirs et de la partage des sensations.

Pour accéder à ce monde en transformation, et sortir de l&apos;impasse des « utilisateurs », on doit à un moment donnée passer par la programmation informatique. Souvent on sous-estime le rôle de la programmation dans les oeuvres interactives, oubliant que l&apos;interactivité nécessite en réalité la création d&apos;un programmes. Malheureusement, l&apos;ordinateur ne créera pas ce programme à notre place. HAL9000 n&apos;existe pas encore, ce qui est plutôt rassurant, mais la plupart du temps embettant pour l&apos;étudiant en « arts plastiques » qui n&apos;a pas forcément envie de devenir ingénieur informatique pour créer des oeuvres artistiques. Heureusement de nombreux artistes ont déjà traversé cette difficulté et ont laissé derrière eux de puissants outils à la fois collectives (le fameux « open-source »), pas chers ($0.00 = 0 euros), et conçus spécifiquement pour des étudiants en art.

Ce cours utilisera le logiciel de programmation artistique Processing. Tous les cours seront basés sur des cours en-ligne du site de l&apos;école (http://www.ecole-art-aix.fr/rubrique81.html), permettant à l&apos;étudiant de revenir à n&apos;importe quel moment sur les concepts et techniques enseignés, mais à son propre rythme. Les cours en-ligne seront révisés sur place, accompagnés d&apos;expérimentations artistiques. La base de Processing est la création d&apos;images et nous accenterons le cours sur ces aspect de l&apos;environement. Mais Processing peut manipuler de nombreuses autres matières : nous traiterons par exemple les entrées audio et vidéo, des programmes en-ligne, et l&apos;interfaçage avec le monde physique via les cartes Arduino (cf. http://arduino.cc).

Méthode d&apos;enseignement
Cours en atelier et cours en-ligne. Démonstration et explication des concepts de base de la programmation, exemples et analyses d&apos;oeuvres interactives, exercises pratiques (individuels et collectifs) en atelier.

Nous devons noter ici qu&apos;aucune connaissance préalable est nécessaire pour suivre ce cours, et rapellons à tout ceux qui auraient fuit les mathématiques en s&apos;inscrivant dans une école d&apos;art, que la programmation n&apos;est pas de la mathématique et peut être un lieu fertile pour l&apos;exploration artistique.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Douglas Edric Stanley</name>
            <email>douglas at abstractmachine dot net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Objets orientés-image</title>
                <url>http://www.ecole-art-aix.fr/rubrique661.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Atelier hypermédia</title>
                <url>http://www.ecole-art-aix.fr/rubrique11.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Processing (cours en ligne)</title>
                <url>http://www.ecole-art-aix.fr/article1215.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>abstractmachine</title>
                <url>http://www.abstractmachine.net/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>L&apos;école supérieure d&apos;art d&apos;Aix-en-Provence</title>
                <url>http://www.ecole-art-aix.fr/</url>
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Septembre - décembre 2007</date>
        <institution>Université du Québec à Montréal</institution>
        <title>Baccalauréat en médias interactifs</title>
        <description>EDM 4610 : Image de synthèse et interactivité&lt;br /&gt;Atelier abordant la conception d&apos;images fixes ou cinétiques à travers des stratégies de production qui ne recourent peu ou pas à la captation. Génération, organisation et construction des éléments picturaux par la synthèse en vue d&apos;une représentation figurée, schématisée ou abstraite et d&apos;une intégration interactive (graphisme ou typographisme, illustration, modélisation, imagerie computationnelle, animation 2D ou 3D). De plus, l&apos;étudiant est appelé à poursuivre sa familiarisation au langage de l&apos;image et à l&apos;organisation picturale en fonction d&apos;un usage interactif, en prêtant attention à la caractérisation des objets formels et à leur mise en espace pour l&apos;écran.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Jean-François Renaud</name>
            <email>renaud dot jean-francois at uqam dot ca</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>EDM4610</title>
                <url>http://multimedia.uqam.ca/cours/edm4610/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Médias interactifs</title>
                <url>http://www.edm.uqam.ca/mi/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>École des médias</title>
                <url>http://www.edm.uqam.ca/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>UQAM</title>
                <url>http://www.uqam.ca/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>April - July 2007</date>
        <institution>Fachhochschule Nordwestschweiz, Institut Medienkunst</institution>
        <title>Aufbaukurs Processing</title>
        <description>Processing wurde als Programmiersprache speziell für Gestalter und Künstler entwickelt. Sie eignet sich speziell für die Programmierung von Bildern, Animation und Sound und führt sehr schnell zu visuell ansprechenden Resultaten. Durch den einfachen Aufbau mit einem einzigen Editierfenster wird einen klarer Blick auf das Grundwesen des Programmierens ermöglicht.
Im Aufbaukurs von Andres Wanner geht es um fortgeschrittene Programmstrukturen, objektorientierte Programmierung, externe Libraries. Der Grundkurs Processing wird vorausgesetzt.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Andres Wanner</name>
            <email>andres dot wanner at fhnw dot ch</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Aufbaukurs Processing</title>
                <url>http://www.pixelstorm.ch/processing/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Institut Medienkunst</title>
                <url>http://www.medienkunst.ch/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>April-June 2007</date>
        <institution>The Art Institutes international Minnesota</institution>
        <title>Special Topics in Interactive Media Design: Alternative Input Devices and Human-Computer Interaction</title>
        <description>This is a seminar class that examines the design issues around new and uncommon modes of interactivity. It introduces students to Processing as a tool for data manipulation and visualization. The course also presents Processing and Arduino for experimenting with input/output hardware.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Tim Armato</name>
            <email>tarmato at aii dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Class Home Page</title>
                <url>http://tma362.aisites.com/IM4490/ST-index.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Class Announcements</title>
                <url>http://tma362.aisites.com/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Mayo 2007</date>
        <institution>I.U.N.A. Multimedia</institution>
        <title>Processing: programación para el arte interactivo. Net.Art e instalaciones interactivas con nuevas tecnologías.</title>
        <description>El objetivo de este curso es capacitar al alumno en la programación con fines artísticos, de forma que este pueda realizar trabajos de Net.Art, con interfaces físicas y de arte interactivo en general. Con tal fin, la meta es enseñar al alumno el lenguaje de programación Processing, el cual fue diseñado para contemplar las necesidades de los artistas relacionados con las nuevas tecnologías.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Emiliano Causa</name>
            <email>e_causa at yahoo dot com dot ar</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>I.U.N.A. Multimedia</title>
                <url>http://iuna.edu.ar/departamentos/multimedia/investiga/cursos-posgrado.htm</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Emiliano Causa</title>
                <url>http://www.emiliano-causa.com.ar/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2007</date>
        <institution>UCLA</institution>
        <title>Interactivity (DESMA 28)</title>
        <description>This course is an introduction to the concepts and principles of interactivity and to software as a medium for expression and communication. It focuses on developing the skills required for creating interactive work, therefore participants will work toward developing their computer programming skills within the context of visual media. The concepts and skills taught in the class will enhance each participant&apos;s ability to excel in future UCLA classes about the Internet, animation, interactive media, and game design.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Casey Reas</name>
            <email>reas at ucla dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Class website</title>
                <url>http://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Spring07/28/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>UCLA D|MA</title>
                <url>http://dma.ucla.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Autumn 2007</date>
        <institution>The College of Fine Arts, UNSW - Australia</institution>
        <title>Design and Computers 4</title>
        <description>The course aims to develop a digital design practice, which supports you to integrate technical knowledge and skills with tools, processes and appropriate software/hardware solutions as a standard part of a contemporary digital design discipline. This course is instrumentalist in direction, exploring and developing interactive processes for the screen. Projects will address conceptual, processes and technical understandings of a digital interactive design and layout production.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Paul Jebanasam</name>
            <email>paul at omnium dot net dot au</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Design and Computers 4</title>
                <url>http://www.staff.cofa.unsw.edu.au/~bradmiller/physical_computing/D&amp;C4_index.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>12-30 de Marzo</date>
        <institution>Centro Multimedia - Centro Nacional de Las Artes de México</institution>
        <title>&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;PROGRAMACIÓN DE GRÁFICAS PARA PRINCIPIANTES</title>
        <description>En este curso se utilizará Processing para explorar los conceptos básicos de la programación aplicados a la síntesis de imagen, animaciones, e interfases interactivas. &lt;br /&gt;Entrada Libre&lt;br /&gt;</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Jaime Villarreal</name>
            <email>jesusjaime at gmail dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>http://cmm.cenart.gob.mx/cursos/</title>
                <url>http://cmm.cenart.gob.mx/cursos/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>March 14-16, 2007</date>
        <institution>F+F Schule für Kunst und Mediendesign Zürich</institution>
        <title>Processing</title>
        <description>As an introduction, Andres Wanner makes students draw with digital means. Processing makes it very easy to program lines and forms. Many key issues of programming are learnt and transformed into small visual applications.
After that, the aim is to use the specific properties of the computer as a medium for visual purposes. What does it mean to draw images by means of an algorithmic code, instead of drawing them by hand? Examples from the history of computer art will be shown and discussed.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Andres Wanner</name>
            <email>andres dot wanner at fhnw dot ch</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>F+F Schule</title>
                <url>http://www.ffzh.ch/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Course Page</title>
                <url>http://www.pixelstorm.ch/processing/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>3/3/2007</date>
        <institution>Master in Multimedia - University of Florence (Italy)</institution>
        <title>Programming for non programmers</title>
        <description>The course&apos;s main objective is to introduce students without a programming background to the basic concepts of structured and object-oriented programming. The course adopts a learning by example approach, thus we start from simple processing applets that show the basic of displaying and drawing graphic primitives, followed by more complex applications where images, videos and sounds are also used.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>walter nunziati</name>
            <email>nunziati at dsi dot unifi dot it</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Master in Multimedia home page (in italian)</title>
                <url>http://www.mastermultimedia.unifi.it/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Course description (in italian)</title>
                <url>http://www.mastermultimedia.unifi.it/coursebox.php?F=nunziati_corso&amp;KeepThis=true&amp;TB_iframe=true&amp;height=400&amp;width=600</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Teacher\&apos;s home page</title>
                <url>http://viplab.dsi.unifi.it/~nunziati/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>2006-2007</date>
        <institution>Faculty of the Arts, Thames Valley University. London. UK.</institution>
        <title>Experimental Digital Media</title>
        <description>The MA in Computer Arts at Thames Valley University teaches processing,  arduino and wiring on a couple of courses: Experimental Digital Media and Computer Principles for Artists.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Ian Grant</name>
            <email>ian dot grant at tvu dot ac dot uk</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Thames Valley University</title>
                <url>http://www.tvu.ac.uk/index.jsp</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Example Work</title>
                <url>http://ellington.tvu.ac.uk/ma/category/modules/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>MA in Computer Arts</title>
                <url>http://mercury.tvu.ac.uk/ca</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>January 2007</date>
        <institution>Ecole supérieure des Arts - Mons (Belgium)</institution>
        <title>Applied Science : Computer Science (part 2)</title>
        <description>The course is taught in the third year of the Digital Arts section in the continuity of part one of the programming class. This second part explores interactive systems and specific programming techniques with the help of the Arduino interface (www.arduino.cc) in standalone as well as in association with Processing software. Different modules, covering simple sensors, actuators and display systems, to name a few, will be covered and could be assembled into larger projects. Basic electric and electronic knowledge will also given so the students could develop their own systems.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Stephan Delattre</name>
            <email>stephan dot delattre at gmail dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>January 2007</date>
        <institution>Ecole supérieure des Arts - Mons (Belgium)</institution>
        <title>Applied Science : Computer Science (part 1)</title>
        <description>This course is an introduction to computer programming using Processing. Taught in the second year of the Digital Arts section and oriented to an artistic audience, the main focus is about general programming structures, including object oriented programming. The idea is to develop students abilities and skills in computer programming and help them developing their own projects. After a few lectures, the class will be mostly organized as a workshop, each student developing a personal project and evolving his (her) own pace.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Stephan Delattre</name>
            <email>stephan dot delattre at gmail dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>14. Nov. 2006</date>
        <institution>Interface Culture Linz Austria</institution>
        <title>Visual Programming</title>
        <description>Master students explore the concepts of algorithmic art. As a basis the history of illusion (Shadow Play, Laterna Magica, Absolute film by Ruttmann, Fischinger, Richter, McLaren et al. up to modern algorithmic art) is taught.
Mathematical concepts for generative computer graphics (Noise, Perlin Noise, L-Systems, Recursion, Subdivision, Cellular Automata, Spring – Mass – Damper Systems, ...) will be explained and experimented with.
Modern techniques like Fragment/Vertex Shaders are integrated in the works to lead to new possibilities in aesthetics.
Processing will be the tool to enable all this , resulting in a generative 3D stereo art exhibition.
thx to the proce55ing team !!!</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Robert Praxmarer</name>
            <email>cubic at servus dot at</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Interface Culture</title>
                <url>http://www.ufg.ac.at/portal/DE/institut_fuer_medien/masterstudium_interface_culture/index.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Robert Praxmarer</title>
                <url>http://www.servus.at/cubic</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>2-3 Dec 2006</date>
        <institution>Le centre de Ressources Art Sensitif à Mains d&apos;Oeuvres</institution>
        <title>Initiation à Processing</title>
        <description>L&apos;atelier permettra de découvrir le logiciel et ses fonctionnalités, et initiera les participants à la création de modules simples.

Il est indispensable d&apos;amener son ordinateur.

Formateurs : Julien Gachadoat, avec la collaboration de Jean-Noël Montagné.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Julien Gachadoat</name>
            <email>me at v3ga dot net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Le centre de Ressources Art Sensitif</title>
                <url>http://www.craslab.org/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>03.11.2006</date>
        <institution>UdK Berlin</institution>
        <title>Gestalten Mit Code / Spiele für Linus</title>
        <description>Linus is almost 4 years old and loves reactive objects.
&lt;br/&gt;
As long as he can project into these objects he doesn t care whether they are virtual representations, physical objects or mental images.
&lt;br/&gt;
Since he can t read, instruction manuals don t mean that much to him. Since he can t count very well, scores don t mean much either.
&lt;br/&gt;
He is not afraid of doing something wrong, still his vocabulary of metaphors of digital interaction is limited.
&lt;br/&gt;
The course will end with a visit from Linus.
&lt;br/&gt;
The objective of the course is to explore and investigate techniques and concepts of how to create game-like and playful situations.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Dennis Paul</name>
            <email>d3 at magnetspeicher dot de</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Gestalten Mit Code</title>
                <url>http://www.wortwechsel.biz/gestaltenmitcode/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2006</date>
        <institution>Royal College of Art</institution>
        <title>MA Design Interactions</title>
        <description>Processing is being utilised as an introduction to computer programming for students from diverse creative backgrounds. During the progression of the workshop series various topics are being explored, including imagery, sound, animation, networking, data visualisations, digital typography, mobile devices and physical computing. The module also discusses both historical and contemporary examples of computer usage in art and design and encourages a critical approach towards conceptual aspects of the field.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>David Muth</name>
            <email>david at soda dot co dot uk</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Royal College of Art</title>
                <url>http://www.rca.ac.uk/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>MA Design Interactions</title>
                <url>http://www.interaction.rca.ac.uk/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2006</date>
        <institution>Ravensbourne College of Design and Communication</institution>
        <title>MA Interactive Digital Media</title>
        <description>During the first semester of the MA programme students will be introduced to computer programming as creative expression. Workshops explore various topics, including imagery, sound, animation, networking, data visualisations, digital typography and interfacing with physical devices. The module also encourages a critical approach towards conceptual aspects of code art culture.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>David Muth</name>
            <email>david at soda dot co dot uk</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Ravensbourne College of Design and Communication</title>
                <url>http://www.rave.ac.uk/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>MA Interactive Digital Media</title>
                <url>http://www.maidm.com/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Oct 24 - Nov 24 2006</date>
        <institution>FHNW, Medienkunst</institution>
        <title>Programmierung 3.0</title>
        <description>Processing ist eine Programmiersprache, die speziell für Gestalter und Künstler entwickelt wurde. Sie führt sehr schnell zu visuell ansprechenden Resultaten. Durch den einfachen Aufbau mit einem einzigen Editierfenster wird einen klarer Blick auf das Grundwesen des Programmierens ermöglicht.

Inhalte:
- Programmieren von Grund auf verstehen lernen
- effizienter und strukturierter Programmieren
- Variablen und Datentypen
- Listen und Schleifen
- Modularisieren mit Funktionen und Prozeduren</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Andres Wanner</name>
            <email>andres dot wanner at fhnw dot ch</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Medienkunst</title>
                <url>http://www.medienkunst.ch/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Computing</title>
                <url>http://147.86.68.141/~wanner/computing/index.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Oct 1, 2006</date>
        <institution>Istanbul Technical University Architecture Department</institution>
        <title>ITE Computational Design Workshop</title>
        <description>Four day computational design workshop at Istanbul Technical University Architecture Department. An introduction to the fundamentals of computer programming within the context of dynamic visual compositions. Undergraduate students particularly explore macro compositions with details at the micro level.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Burak Arikan</name>
            <email>arikan at media dot mit dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>ITE</title>
                <url>http://ite.dugumkume.org/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Burak Arikan</title>
                <url>http://burak-arikan.com/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Winter Term 2006/07</date>
        <institution>University of the Arts Bremen</institution>
        <title>Program &amp; Process. Introduction to Programming Pictures</title>
        <description>This course is offered to students, third semester and up, of the joint B.A. and B.Sc. program in Digital Media at the University of the Arts, and the University of Bremen, plus two other schools (in German). It is meant as an alternative to the regular introduction to computing. Algorithms, programs, pictures, and aesthetics are its key concepts. Processing is used as the tool to fix ideas and put them onto the machine.

We start from two kinds of elements: algorithms and pictures. From there we approach programs as the syntactically fixed units in which any computable operation must be described if it is to be performed by a computer.

Students will be exposed to the different ways of thinking and conceptualizing in algorithmics and aesthetics – but not to quarrel about one against the other. Rather, examples from the history of algorithmic art should demonstrate that in the field of digital media, it is algorithms and art, and thus familiarity with the two controversial ways of thinking is to the heart of the field.

The dialectics of static programs and dynamic processes will build another thread running through the entire semester. We will see that technical knowledge is enshrined to a large extent in rules. Rules in the formal disciplines, like mathematics, are of a general nature, and request to accept them as valid. Rules in the informal disciplines, like graphic design, are of a special nature. They make situational and context-rich exemplars.

Participants must be active members of the group. There will be frequent assignments plus a term project to be presented at the fine final session.

Starts October 17, 2006, and runs through to February 6,2007.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Frieder Nake</name>
            <email>nake at informatik dot uni-bremen dot de</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall/Winter 2006/2007</date>
        <institution>FH W-S / University of Applied Sciences / Fachbereich Gestaltung</institution>
        <title>Introduction to Processing</title>
        <description>The course is a step-by-step introduction to the processing language and the principles of computational design. No programming experience is needed.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Daniel Rothaug</name>
            <email>rothaug at zumkuckuck dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>University Website</title>
                <url>http://www.fh-wuerzburg.de/gestaltung/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2006</date>
        <institution>UCLA Design | Media Arts</institution>
        <title>Programming Media I</title>
        <description>The theme for this class is Visual Music and each participant will create a live, visual accompaniment for a sound composition. There is one major project for the quarter, but it has many parts. Each participant will select an audio composition from a provided list and will spend the next 10 weeks developing and documenting a live, visual performance.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>C.E.B. Reas</name>
            <email>reas at ucla dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://classes.design.ucla.edu/Fall06/152AC/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2006</date>
        <institution>UCLA Design | Media Arts</institution>
        <title>Interactivity</title>
        <description>This course is an introduction to the concepts and principles of interactivity. In addition to discussing ideas related to interactivity, the class focuses on developing the skills required for creating interactive work, therefore participants will work toward developing their computer programming skills. The concepts and skills taught in the class will enhance each participant\&apos;s ability to excel in future UCLA classes about the Internet, animation, interactive media, and game design.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>C.E.B. Reas</name>
            <email>reas at ucla dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://classes.design.ucla.edu/Fall06/28/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Oct 1, 2006</date>
        <institution>Dugumkume</institution>
        <title>ITE Computational Design Workshop</title>
        <description>One day computational design workshop at 20ML in Istanbul by Burak Arikan and Dara Kilicoglu. An introduction to the fundamentals of computer programming within the context of dynamic visual compositions.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Burak Arikan</name>
            <email>arikan at media dot mit dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>ITE</title>
                <url>http://ite.dugumkume.org/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Dugumkume</title>
                <url>http://www.dugumkume.org/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall, 2006</date>
        <institution>Miami University of Ohio</institution>
        <title>Aesthetics + Computation</title>
        <description>Designed primarily for a creative population (non-programmers,) this course presents an introduction to the syntax and semantics of the Processing programming language, as well as an introduction to computational aesthetics. The course assumes no prior programming experience, although a basic working knowledge of computer graphics application software is assumed (e.g. PhotoShop.) Through a series of lectures, hands-on tutorials and critiques, students will be exposed to fundamental graphics programming concepts and techniques, including basic object-oriented programming. Whenever possible, programming examples will be conceptually and creatively based.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Ira</name>
            <email>greenbi at muohio dot du</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>interactive media studies | miami</title>
                <url>http://student.sba.muohio.edu/ims/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>09/25/2006</date>
        <institution>Arts et Technologies de L Image. Université Paris 8</institution>
        <title>Generative and Evolutionary Art</title>
        <description>Processing est utilisé comme outil pour les cours en Art Génératif et Art Evolutionniste. Etudiants en Master 1.
---------------------------------------------
Processing is used as a tool for the courses about Generative Art and Evolutionary Art.
Students in Master 1.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Alain Lioret</name>
            <email>alainlioret at wanadoo dot fr</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Alain Lioret</title>
                <url>http://www.alainlioret.com/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2006</date>
        <institution>ITIP, New York University</institution>
        <title>Nature of Code</title>
        <description>Can we capture the unpredictable evolutionary and emergent properties of nature in software? Can understanding the mathematical principles behind our physical world world help us to create digital worlds? This class will focus on the programming strategies and techniques behind computer simulations of natural systems. We’ll explore topics ranging from basic mathematics and physics concepts to more advanced simulations of complex systems. Subjects covered will include forces, trigonometry, fractals, cellular automata, self-organization, and genetic algorithms. Examples will be demonstrated using Processing with a focus on object oriented programming.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Daniel Shiffman</name>
            <email>daniel dot shiffman at nyu dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course Website</title>
                <url>http://www.shiffman.net/teaching/the-nature-of-code</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2006</date>
        <institution>New York University</institution>
        <title>Introduction to Computational Media</title>
        <description>What can computation add to human communication? Creating computer applications, instead of just using them, will give you a deeper understanding of the essential possibilities of computation. This requires that you learn to program the computer. The first few weeks of this course focus on four very basic programming concepts, if statements, repeat loops, variables and routines. The Java-based ‘Processing’ graphical programming environment is the primary vehicle for the class. Another programming language and environment will also be introduced very quickly to show the generality of these programming concepts using a different environment and syntax. Weekly assignments are required through most of the semester. The end of the semester is spent developing an idea for a final project and implementing it using computer programming.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Daniel Shiffman</name>
            <email>daniel dot shiffman at nyu dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course Website</title>
                <url>http://itp.nyu.edu/icm/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Syllabus</title>
                <url>http://www.shiffman.net/teaching/icm/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Textbook Project</title>
                <url>http://book.shiffman.net/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>[ 09.07.06 ]</date>
        <institution>UNION COLLEGE</institution>
        <title>[ The Proce55ed Pixel ]</title>
        <description>Utilizing basic aspects of computer programming, this course will explore how artists can use code to explore a variety of content in computer graphics.  By means of the programming environment proce55ing and Macromedia’s Action Scripting, students will investigate issues in animation, computational design, gaming, interactivity, and other relevant topics.  Instruction will take place through examples, technical demos, readings, discussions, and several projects.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>fernando orellana</name>
            <email>orellana at gmail dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Class Website:</title>
                <url>http://cs.union.edu/ava270</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Fernando Orellana</title>
                <url>http://www.fernandoorellana.com/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Jul 22-December 2006</date>
        <institution>Srishti School of Art,Design and Technology,Bangalore</institution>
        <title>Programming for poets</title>
        <description>The course introduces programming concepts to art+design students.The course\\\&apos;s primary aim is to look at coding as an aesthetic practice.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>yashas</name>
            <email>yashas at intersections dot in</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course webpage</title>
                <url>http://www.intersections.in/wiki/index.php?n=Main.ProgrammingForPoets</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>17 a 21 de julio de 2006</date>
        <institution>Fundación de Arte Contemporáneo (Montevideo-Uruguay)</institution>
        <title>La imagen calculada</title>
        <description>A partir de la naturaleza numérica de la imagen en movimiento y sus diferentes usos se desarrollarán diversas estrategias de producción, manipulación y exhibición con la herramienta video.

1)La imagen digital
2)Creación de objetos audiovisuales
3)Programación para artistas y diseñadores -Introducción a Processing-</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Enrique Aguerre</name>
            <email>enriqueaguerre at gmail dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Fundación de Arte Contemporáneo</title>
                <url>http://www.facmvd.org/actividades/2006/julio/mvd-digital.htm</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>12-14 june 2006</date>
        <institution>Médias-Cité, Bordeaux[FR]</institution>
        <title>Introduction à Processing</title>
        <description>Cet atelier permettra d’aborder l’environnement processing pour ses capacités à créer des applications interactives. L’animation de l’atelier sera assuré par Julien Gachadoat (http://v3ga.net). L’atelier alternera entre temps d’apprentissages et temps de pratiques accompagnées permettant aux participants de travailler à une première création/réalisation. L’accent sera mis sur l’échange de savoirs et d’expériences entre participants, intervenants et organisateurs.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Julien Gachadoat</name>
            <email>me at v3ga dot net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Article Médias-cité</title>
                <url>http://www.medias-cite.org/article.php3?id_article=484</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>May 4, 2006</date>
        <institution>Instituto Universitario Nacional de Arte (Buenos Aires - Argentina)</institution>
        <title>Processing: programación para el arte interactivo. Net.Art e instalaciones interactivas con nuevas tecnologías.</title>
        <description>El objetivo de este curso es capacitar al alumno en la programación con fines artísticos, de forma que este pueda realizar trabajos de Net.Art y de arte interactivo en general. Con tal fin, la meta es enseñar al alumno el lenguaje de programación Processing, el cual fue diseñado para contemplar las necesidades de los artistas relacionados con las nuevas tecnologías.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Emiliano Causa</name>
            <email>e_causa at yahoo dot com dot ar</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Curso:Processing: programación para el arte interactivo.I.U.N.A.</title>
                <url>http://www.proyecto-biopus.com.ar/emiliano/catedras2006/processing/index.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2006</date>
        <institution>IUAV - Istituto Universitario di Architettura di Venezia</institution>
        <title>Informatica: Media Processing in Processing</title>
        <description>A course on fundamentals of image/sound processing and graphic programming explained by means of the free language and environment Processing.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Davide Rocchesso</name>
            <email>davide dot rocchesso at univr dot it</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course material in English</title>
                <url>http://cnx.org/content/col10268/latest/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Course material in Italian</title>
                <url>http://cnx.org/content/col10299/latest/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Official course page</title>
                <url>http://www.iuav.it/Didattica1/pagine-web/facolt--di1/Davide-Roc/claVES---i/index.htm</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Teacher profile</title>
                <url>http://cnx.org/member_profile/drocchesso</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2006</date>
        <institution>UdK Berlin</institution>
        <title>Gestalten Mit Code ( Designing With Code )</title>
        <description>in this course we will explore tools that enable us to express thoughts, ideas and concepts in code.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Dennis Paul</name>
            <email>d3 at magnetspeicher dot de</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>University Website</title>
                <url>http://www.digital.udk-berlin.de/de/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Last Semester s Wiki ( german )</title>
                <url>http://entropie.digital.udk-berlin.de/wiki/GestaltenMitCode</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2006</date>
        <institution>FH W-S / University of Applied Sciences / Fachbereich Gestaltung</institution>
        <title>Introduction to Processing</title>
        <description>The course is a step-by-step introduction to the processing language and the principles of computational design. No programming experience is needed.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Daniel Rothaug</name>
            <email>rothaug at zumkuckuck dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>University Website</title>
                <url>http://www.fh-wuerzburg.de/gestaltung/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>October 2006 to September 2007</date>
        <institution>Goldsmiths College, University of London</institution>
        <title>MA in Interactive Media, Critical Theory and Practice</title>
        <description>The MA Interactive Media provides students with an opportunity to respond creatively (at a theoretical and practical level) to the interaction between connecting fields of aesthetics, science, biology, philosophy, commerce, media production, design and architecture

Students draw on the conceptual work discussed in the post-structuralist theories of Foucault, Deleuze and Guattari, Irigaray, Elisabeth Grosz, Serres, Greg Lynn, Massumi, DeLanda, Bergson, classic and contemporary media theory such as McLuhan, Kittler, Virilio, Lev Manovich, Peter Weibel, Pierre Levy, and theories of scientific interaction including Shannon, Weiner, Varela and Maturana, Prigogine, Darwinism and endosymbiosis. 

The MA also connects students to a strong network of visiting lectures on bioart, robotics, performance, virtual architecture, media arts, social networks, and machinic interaction. Alongside the theory programme there is a closely related programme of visiting practitioners in the field of interactive media art, telemedicine, viral branding, video games, performance and installation art, and sound design.

We offer a specific emphasis on the making: making concepts, making media artefacts, installations and interactive experiences. Half of the final dissertation is based on practical work that students make and exhibit. It offers training in the application of media technologies for the purpose of creating practical conceptually grounded work in the final show.  In common with Goldsmiths over-arching commitment to interdisciplinarity, Students can chose optional courses from the vast range of MA offered at Goldsmiths.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Luciana Parisi</name>
            <email>cus01lp at gold dot ac dot uk</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Goldsmiths College MA Interactive Media</title>
                <url>http://www.goldsmiths.ac.uk/study-options/postgraduate/MA-Interactive-Media-Critical-Theory-Practice.php</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>march 5, 06</date>
        <institution>University of Colorado, Boulder</institution>
        <title>Digital Art 2: Machinima, Software Art, Future</title>
        <description>This course will introduce students to three different areas of digital art. The course begins with an assignment using machinima, a method of narrative storytelling using 3-D digital games. The course then shifts its focus to software art and includes a number of demos and an assigment using Processing, a scripting language based on Java developed at MIT especially for visual artists.Finally we end the course with a an assignment about the future of the environment.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Anne-Marie Schleiner</name>
            <email>opensorcery at opensorcery dot net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course</title>
                <url>http://www.opensorcery.net/skool/digart206.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Semester 2 2005/2006</date>
        <institution>Faculty of the Arts - Thames Valley University, London, UK</institution>
        <title>Creative Coding (Introduction to programming for artists and designers)</title>
        <description>Creative Coding (Introduction to programming for artists and designers) gives students (year 1) of BA Digital Arts key technical skills and understanding in programming and computational media in the context of design and art. It provides students with the necessary knowledge and experience so that they can begin to use code in functional and expressive ways.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Mitja Kostomaj</name>
            <email>mitja dot kostomaj at tvu dot ac dot uk</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Winter 2006</date>
        <institution>UCLA</institution>
        <title>School of Architecture Research Studio</title>
        <description>The research studio at UCLA is a year long studio taken during the last year of a students graduate studies. Weekly processing workshops are used to develop and support the students explorations of computation in their studio projects.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>John Houck</name>
            <email>jdhouck at yahoo dot com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>UCLA Architecture</title>
                <url>http://www.aud.ucla.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2006</date>
        <institution>ITP -- New York University</institution>
        <title>The Nature of Code</title>
        <description>Can we capture the unpredictable evolutionary and emergent properties of nature in software? Can understanding the mathematical principles behind our physical world world help us to create digital worlds? This class will focus on the programming strategies and techniques behind computer simulations of natural systems. We’ll explore topics ranging from basic mathematics and physics concepts to more advanced simulations of complex systems. Subjects covered will include forces, trigonometry, fractals, cellular automata, self-organization, and genetic algorithms. Examples will be demonstrated using Processing with a focus on object oriented programming.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Daniel Shiffman</name>
            <email>daniel dot shiffman at nyu dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course Website</title>
                <url>http://www.shiffman.net/teaching/the-nature-of-code/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>January 2006</date>
        <institution>California Institute of the Arts</institution>
        <title>Intro to Computational Concepts</title>
        <description>This workshop introduced graduate and undergraduate level graphic design students to the fundamentals of code through a series of direct, visual exercises. We explored computational concepts in print, motion, and interaction through the Processing environment.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Peter Cho</name>
            <email>peter at pcho dot net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Computational Concepts</title>
                <url>http://www.pcho.net/calarts/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2005</date>
        <institution>Aix-en-Provence School of Art</institution>
        <title>L&apos;image-algorithme : Introduction à la programmation graphique avec Processing</title>
        <description>This class builds off our popular class on interactivity using Macromedia Director. As the role of the Atelier Hypermedia is to act as an interface to the other networked ateliers in the school (Sound, 3d, Robotics, Electronics, Video, Printmaking), we will be focusing not only on the interactive visual aspects of Processing, but also its use as a creative tool. There will be an online component, with tutorials and student examples, as is the tradition in our atelier. Also following tradition, outside participants are welcome on a first-come-first-serve basis, with a few slots open every year for the passionately determined. There is no fee. You will have to be proficient in French to attend.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Douglas Edric Stanley</name>
            <email>destanley@abstractmachine.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Atelier</title>
                <url>http://www.ecole-art-aix.fr/hypermedia/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Course Website</title>
                <url>http://www.ecole-art-aix.fr/rubrique.php3?id_rubrique=81</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Student Work</title>
                <url>http://www.ecole-art-aix.fr/rubrique.php3?id_rubrique=84</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Autumn 2005</date>
        <institution>Ravensbourne School of Design and Communication</institution>
        <title />
        <description>During the first semester of the MA Interactive Digital Media Processing will be utilised introduce students to programming as creative expression. Workshops explore various applications including imagery, sound, networking, data visualisations and digital typography. The module also encourages a critical approach to conceptual aspects of code art culture.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>David Muth</name>
            <email>david@soda.co.uk</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Ravensbourne</title>
                <url>http://www.rave.ac.uk/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>MAIDM</title>
                <url>http://maidm.net/wiki/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Winter 2005</date>
        <institution>University of Copenhagen, Dept. of Art and Cultural Science</institution>
        <title>The Biosemiotic View</title>
        <description>This postgraduate course will give the students an introduction to code in both software and wetware.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Mogens Jacobsen</name>
            <email>jacobsen@artnode.org</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://www.0ooo0.info</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2005</date>
        <institution>Portuguese Catholic University - Porto</institution>
        <title>Multimedia Programming</title>
        <description>The Multimedia Programming course is an introduction to computer programming. Previous programming experience is not required. This course aims at giving students an opportunity to acquire the basic concepts about algorithms and programming languages. Students will be encouraged to structure their way of thinking in order to solve problems through computer programming. We will use the Processing programming language - an image, sound and animation programming language - to put to practice the discussed concepts. The final goal of this course is to give students the conceptual tools to approach other programming languages easily.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Jorge Cardoso</name>
            <email>jccardoso@porto.ucp.pt</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course Website (in Portuguese)</title>
                <url>http://soundserver.porto.ucp.pt/aulas/tiki-index.php?page=PaginaProgramacaoMultimedia</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>3rd October 2005</date>
        <institution>University of Dundee</institution>
        <title>Engineering Software (EG21003)</title>
        <description>An Introduction to physical computing for product design and mechanical engineering students. The module brief is to make me a mobile phone exploring both graphical and physical ways to communicate. Processing is introcuded alongside microcontrollers, card, string, paper and jelly (concrete will be brought in at some point in the near future).</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Jon Rogers</name>
            <email>j.rogers@dundee.ac.uk</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>www.idl.dundee.ac.uk/~jon</title>
                <url>http://www.idl.dundee.ac.uk/~jon</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2005</date>
        <institution>University of New South Wales</institution>
        <title>College of Fine Arts</title>
        <description>A full day workshop for students wishing to learn the the core concepts of computer programming using the Processing language. Focus will be placed on its application in sound and image based work and the course material will include details of the most fundamental topics along with the more advanced code involved in object oriented programming and implementation of 3rd party libraries.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Paul</name>
            <email>z3168848@student.unsw.edu.au</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2005</date>
        <institution>Royal College of Art</institution>
        <title>MA Interaction Design</title>
        <description>Processing is being utilised as an introduction to basic concepts of computer programming for students from diverse creative backgrounds. During the progression of the workshop series various possible applications are being explored - including imagery, video, data visualisation, code driven animation, locative media, networking and interfacing with Max/MSP. The module also discusses both historical and contemporary examples of computational art and encourages a critical approach towards conceptual aspects of code art culture.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>David Muth</name>
            <email>david@soda.co.uk</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Interaction Design at the Royal College of Art</title>
                <url>http://www.interaction.rca.ac.uk/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>20-23 June 2005</date>
        <institution>MediaLabMadrid</institution>
        <title>Making Things Move</title>
        <description>How can we make things move in an interesting, compelling, and lifelike manner? We will investigate key concepts of programmatic animation techniques using processing, an environment for learning about code. We will explore explicit non-linear, sinusoidal and key frame approaches. Then we will examine implicit models for motion, including particle systems, springs, vector fields, collision detection and flocking. In the end, we will find ways of assembling these various approaches to create creatures and objects that move and respond in an elegant and natural manner through their fictional world. Close attention will be paid to exploring how these approaches integrate with interactive and audiovisual systems to create intuitive and playful modes of expression.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Zachary Lieberman</name>
            <email>zlieb@parsons.edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Workshop Annoucement</title>
                <url>http://www.medialabmadrid.org/medialab/medialab.php?l=0&amp;a=a&amp;i=242</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2005</date>
        <institution>Bandung Institute of Technology (ITB)</institution>
        <title>Department of Visual Art: Digital Printmaking (Seni Cetak Digital)</title>
        <description>This undergraduate course introduces printmaking major into digital and electronic art beyond traditional printmaking media. Students are asked to make their own work in video, the Web, or programming media. Students are also introduced to the fundamentals of computer programming within the context of visual form, drawing, and responsive form using Processing.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>widianto nugroho</name>
            <email>wnugroho at itb.ac.id</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://cmd.art.itb.ac.id/scd</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Art Dept. Website</title>
                <url>http://www.art.itb.ac.id</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>University Website</title>
                <url>http://www.itb.ac.id</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2005</date>
        <institution>UCLA</institution>
        <title>Programming Media II (DESMA 152B, 252B)</title>
        <description>A continued introduction to computer programming within the context of image and interaction. Each student&apos;s foundation in basic programming will serve as a platform from which to explore diverse media applications including video, sound, print, networking, data visualization, and other potential areas of their own choice.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>C.E.B. Reas</name>
            <email>reas at ucla dot edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://classes.design.ucla.edu/Spring05/152BC/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>UCLA Design | Media Arts</title>
                <url>http://dma.ucla.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2005</date>
        <institution>Helsinki University of Technology</institution>
        <title>Introduction to computer graphics (T-111.210 Informaatioverkostot: Studio 4)</title>
        <description>Students with basic experience in programming experimented with different aspects of computer graphics by doing four exercises using the Processing-environment and by writing essays.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Tapio Takala</name>
            <email>tapio.takala at hut dot fi</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Exercises</title>
                <url>http://www.tml.hut.fi/Opinnot/T-111.210/processingportfolios/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2005</date>
        <institution>Royal Danish Academy of Fine Arts</institution>
        <title>Copenhagen</title>
        <description>Introduction to programmimg as a tool for artistic expression. Introduction to the programming language Processing.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Mikkel Woldike Breum</name>
            <email>req@jooze.dk</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Summer 2005</date>
        <institution>Hochschule fuer Angewandte Wissenschaft Hamburg, Fachbereich Gestaltung</institution>
        <title>Computergestuetztes Arbeiten - Digital Design Worlds</title>
        <description>The course &apos;Digital Design Worlds&apos; covers the basic principles of using the computer as a design tool. Research will explore specific design methods using the computer not only as a tool but also the computer as a medium. Additional themes explored will be the &apos;disappearing computer&apos; and alteranative input and output methods.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Franziska Huebler</name>
            <email>franziska.truthdare.de</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>University Website</title>
                <url>http://www.haw-hamburg.de/Fachbereich_Gestaltung.5.0.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2005</date>
        <institution>Fachbereich Gestaltung Fachhochschule Wuerzburg-Schweinfurt / University of Applied Sciences</institution>
        <title>Introduction to Processing</title>
        <description>The course is a step-by-step introduction to the processing language and the principles of computational design. No programming experience is needed.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Daniel Rothaug</name>
            <email>rothaug@zumkuckuck.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>University Website</title>
                <url>http://www.fh-wuerzburg.de/gestaltung/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2005</date>
        <institution>School of the Art Institute of Chicago, Department of Art and Technology Studies</institution>
        <title>Programming for Automatic Drawing Systems</title>
        <description>In this course, we juxtapose traditional practices of analog drawing with the process of sketching in code. Technically, the course will introduce the fundamentals of computer programming within a visual context through the development of an online software sketchbook. The first five tutorials are based in Lingo (Director) the second five are based in Processing (alpha shareware). Studio demonstrations will include: software that responds to environmental changes (temperature, oxygen, light), animations that change based on mouse input, software that draws from online data, and software that draws from a human heartbeat.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Tiffany Holmes</name>
            <email>tholme@artic.edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Class Website</title>
                <url>http://www.tiffanyholmes.com/Teaching/PADrawing/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>2004-2005</date>
        <institution>Elisava School of Design</institution>
        <title>Introduction to Programming</title>
        <description>This postgraduate course gives an introduction to the programming world to graduates of Design, Art and Architecture. The object of the course is to give basic programming skills and to give a base to the students so they can use the programming tools in the real world along the course.</description>
        <contact>
            <name />
            <email>federico@area3.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course Website</title>
                <url>http://elisava.es/elisava/fla_ing/continguts/estudis/mp.asp?id=41</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2004</date>
        <institution>Univerity of Washington - Center for Digital Arts and Experimental Media</institution>
        <title>Algorithmic Processes in the Arts</title>
        <description>In this course students work through a progression of four major art projects designed to foster a sense of aesthetics and an understanding of code as emergent media. Examination of relevent work, readings, and supplementary assignments develop perspective and relate to the history of art and technology. Advanced concepts such as image processing, chaotic and complex algorithms, emergent behaviors and evolution are also explored.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Stephanie Andrews</name>
            <email>stephnet@u.washington.edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course Website</title>
                <url>http://www.stephnet.org/430/index.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2004</date>
        <institution>Univerity of Virginia</institution>
        <title>Intermediate New Media Studies</title>
        <description>A three week introduction to fundamental programming methods, and algorithmic graphic generation. Students who had never used a script based program were able to overcome their fears by using the examples on the site as a launching point of their own ideas.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Seth Hunter</name>
            <email>seh4b@virginia.edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course Website</title>
                <url>http://www.uvanewmedia.com/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2004</date>
        <institution>University of Copenhagen, Dept. of Art History</institution>
        <title />
        <description>This course is an introduction to computational media for students without any prior experience in programming. We look at some basics in computability - building a Turing Machine out of paper. Then we move on to Design By Numbers and Processing.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Mogens Jacobsen</name>
            <email>jacobsen@artnode.org</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>University Website</title>
                <url>http://www.sis.ku.dk/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Winter 2004</date>
        <institution>University College London, Bartlett School of Architecture</institution>
        <title />
        <description>This postgraduate course examines the relationship between society and environments through the medium of new technology in order to construct emergent digital architecture. The course aim is to take students with little computing experience and give them a foundation in the generation of space, form and behaviour using a range of programming languages and interactive devices. The Bartlett&apos;s experience in social analysis gives the course a unique societal angle on emergent architecture.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Alasdair Turner</name>
            <email>a.turner@ucl.ac.uk</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>University Website</title>
                <url>http://www.vr.ucl.ac.uk/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Winter 2004</date>
        <institution>Universität der Künste Berlin</institution>
        <title>Designing with Digital Media</title>
        <description>Students realize four short projects, each of a two week duration. Processing was used as the primary working environment to demonstrate alternatives to the GUI approach of common authoring systems based on animation. The purely text-based development process leads us to different design solutions.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Ralph Ammer</name>
            <email>ralph@ralphammer.de</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://grundlagen.digital.udk-berlin.de/ws03_04/index_en.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Winter 2004</date>
        <institution>New York University</institution>
        <title>Procedural Painting</title>
        <description>This introductory level course covers the basics of computer programming within the context of images, drawing, and responsive visual forms. Processing will be used as the primary development environment for the class.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Daniel Shiffman</name>
            <email>daniel@shiffman.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course Website</title>
                <url>http://stage.itp.nyu.edu/%7Edts204/ppaint/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Winter 2004</date>
        <institution>N.Y.U Tisch School of Art, ITP</institution>
        <title>Code And Me</title>
        <description>The course helps graduate students of various backgrounds discover why and how they would use code in functional and expressive ways. Architects, Artists, Industrial Designers, Musicians, and Scientists will use Processing during the semester to establish a personal sensibility to coding.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Amit Pitaru</name>
            <email>amit@pitaru.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Winter 2004</date>
        <institution>Pratt Institute, Computer Graphics and Interactive Media</institution>
        <title>Creating Code for Digital Media</title>
        <description>The goal of this course is to help Pratt&apos;s MFA students discover how to write software that furthers their activities as artists and designers. Using Processing, the course introduces a set of concepts, techniques and exercises specifically tailored for visually oriented minds.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Amit Pitaru</name>
            <email>amit@pitaru.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2003</date>
        <institution>University of Roma Tor Vergata</institution>
        <title>Multimodal Interface and Systems</title>
        <description>Students within the Science of Media and Communication department create intriguing and natural interfaces with Processing.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Carlo Giovannella</name>
            <email>mifav@roma2.infn.it</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2003</date>
        <institution>Universität der Künste Berlin</institution>
        <title>Principles of Computational Design</title>
        <description>By teaching the essential qualities of computational form, this course enables the students to question existing models of interaction and explore new spaces in electronic media. Communication goals are achieved through computational processes.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Marius Watz</name>
            <email>amoeba@evolutionzone.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Universität der Künste</title>
                <url>http://www.udk-berlin.de/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://www.evolutionzone.com/udk/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2003</date>
        <institution>Yale School of Architecture</institution>
        <title>Model Based Design</title>
        <description>Model-based design proposes that digital tools can produce documents that describe more than pure form. These digital artifacts are live, interconnected databases of objects with properties and behaviors. This class explores the role of data and formal process in generating such parametric design.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Simon Greenwold</name>
            <email>simon@aproposinteractive.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://www.architecture.yale.edu/872a/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2003</date>
        <institution>New York University</institution>
        <title>Pixels and Bits</title>
        <description>Juxtaposing traditional components of artistic practice with the development of images and interactions starting from the level of the code that defines them. Understanding how values associated with traditional craft play out in the creation of information based objects.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Rebecca Ross</name>
            <email>rebecca@cat.nyu.edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://cat.nyu.edu/%7Erebecca/pixelsandbits/index.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Exercises</title>
                <url>http://cat.nyu.edu/%7Erebecca/pixelsandbits/students/index.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring and Fall 2003</date>
        <institution>University of North Carolina at Asheville</institution>
        <title>Multimedia Arts &amp; Sciences 373, Internet-based Art &amp; Design</title>
        <description>A study of the history, theory, and practice of internet art and design. Identity, conceptualism, performance, hacktivism, narrative, and computational aesthetics are all explored via research, critique, and hands-on creation.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Curt Cloninger</name>
            <email>curt@lab404.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>MMAS 373</title>
                <url>http://www.lab404.com/373/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2003</date>
        <institution>San Francisco Art Institute</institution>
        <title>Artists in Cyberspace</title>
        <description>This course is not a complete overview of Net Art and the Web. Rather, it focuses on using the Web as a medium for publishing work created with Processing, an art and design friendly programming environment. Throughout the course we will also discuss digital media and its place in the art continuum.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Krister Olsson</name>
            <email>krister@tree-axis.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>SFAI website</title>
                <url>http://www.sfai.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2003</date>
        <institution>University of Washingon</institution>
        <title>Algorithmic Processes in Art</title>
        <description>Visual elements such as dot, line, and field are combined with the computational ideas of variables and conditional statements to generate images. The course explores Design By Numbers and Processing, a new Java-based system for algorithmic and interactive visual creation.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Bret Battey</name>
            <email>bbattey@u.washington.edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Center for Digital Arts and Experimental Media</title>
                <url>http://www.washington.edu/dxarts/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2003</date>
        <institution>UMASS Lowell</institution>
        <title>Interactive Data Visualization</title>
        <description>This course provides a detailed description of what visualization is, how it works, how to use it, its role in numerous applications, how to implement and deploy applications using visualizations.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Georges Grinstein</name>
            <email>grinstein@cs.uml.edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>UMASS Lowell CS</title>
                <url>http://www.cs.uml.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Summer 2003</date>
        <institution>N.Y.U Tisch School of Art</institution>
        <title>Code And Me</title>
        <description>The course helps graduate students of various backgrounds discover why and how they would use code in functional and expressive ways. Architects, Artists, Industrial Designers, Musicians, and Scientists will use Processing during the semester to establish a personal sensibility to coding.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Amit Pitaru</name>
            <email>amit@pitaru.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>ITP website</title>
                <url>http://itp.nyu.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>18 April - 14 July 2003</date>
        <institution>Universität der Künste Berlin</institution>
        <title>Principles of Computational Design</title>
        <description>Three month course introducing students to concepts in computational design, using Processing as the main tool.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Marius Watz</name>
            <email>amoeba@evolutionzone.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Universität der Künste</title>
                <url>http://www.udk-berlin.de/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://www.evolutionzone.com/udk/2003spring/index.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>9 April - 28 May</date>
        <institution>Department of Design and Architecture</institution>
        <title>Nagoya City University</title>
        <description>Students without prior programming experience spent six days designing an interaction on the LCD (320x128 pixels) of a cell phone.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Hironobu Fujiyoshi</name>
            <email>hf@cs.chubu.ac.jp</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://www.vision.cs.chubu.ac.jp/Proce55ing/Programming/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2003</date>
        <institution>Ravensbourne School of Design and Communicaton</institution>
        <title />
        <description>Processing used in the Programming and Generative Visualisation Module of the MA Interactive Digital Media to explain basic concepts of computer programming, as well as ideas and strategies of more complex generative processes.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>David Muth</name>
            <email>david@soda.co.uk</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Ravensbourne</title>
                <url>http://www.rave.ac.uk/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>MA Interactive Digital Media</title>
                <url>http://www.rave.ac.uk/postgrad/pg_idm.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>19 May 2003</date>
        <institution />
        <title>Cologne Academy of Media Arts (Kunsthochschule für Medien Köln)</title>
        <description>One day Processing workshop focusing on basic concepts of variables, loops, conditionals, and responding to the mouse.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Boris Müller</name>
            <email>boris@esono.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>KHM website</title>
                <url>http://www.khm.de/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>3 May - 31 May 2003</date>
        <institution>Ateneo de Manila University</institution>
        <title>Computational Media Design Workshop</title>
        <description>Five week workshop introducing principles of computing and visual arts. Processing is used as the base software for instruction. Final projects from this workshop featured in DECODE exhibition of the Ateneo Art Gallery.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Martin Gomez</name>
            <email>martin@decode.ateneo.edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Ateneo de Manila University</title>
                <url>http://www.ateneo.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Workshop website</title>
                <url>http://decode.ateneo.edu/csvaxxx</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>DECODE</title>
                <url>http://decode.ateneo.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>18-20 April 2003</date>
        <institution>Interactive Media Art Laboratory</institution>
        <title>Processing Workshop</title>
        <description>Three day basic Processing workshop at iMAL in Brussels. An introduction to the fundamentals of computer programming within the context of images, drawing, animation, and responsive form.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Casey Reas</name>
            <email>reas@groupc.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>iMAL</title>
                <url>http://www.imal.org/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>11 April 2003</date>
        <institution>Universidad de Los Andes</institution>
        <title>Processing Workshop</title>
        <description>One day workshop in Bogota, Colombia introducing the Processing environment.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Hernando Barragán</name>
            <email>h.barragan@interaction-ivrea.it</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2003</date>
        <institution>MIT</institution>
        <title>Fundamentals of Computational Media Design</title>
        <description>Introduces principles of analysis and synthesis in the computational medium. Expressive examples that illustrate the intersection of computation with the traditional arts are developed on a weekly basis. Hands-on design exercises are continually framed and examined in the larger context of contemporary digital art. Processing is used as one of many tools for creation.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Ben Fry</name>
            <email>fry@media.mit.edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://acg.media.mit.edu/courses/mas110/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2003</date>
        <institution>CCAC</institution>
        <title>Investigative Studio, &apos;Programming Design&apos;</title>
        <description>One semester course at the California College of Arts and Crafts using DBN and Processing, focusing on giving designers the programming skills to create simple tools to facilitate creative exploration.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Krister Olsson</name>
            <email>krister@tree-axis.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://www.tree-axis.com/pd_spring_2003</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>6 February- 3 July 2003</date>
        <institution>Ecole Romande d&apos;Arts et Communication</institution>
        <title>Concepteurs Multimedia</title>
        <description>Processing used in the introduction to programming class for &apos;Concepteurs Multimedia&apos; at the Ecole Romande d&apos;Arts et Communication (Eracom) in Lausanne, Switzerland. The goal is to get the students comfortable with and excited about programming.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Adrien Cater</name>
            <email>adrien@boring.ch</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>9 February 2003</date>
        <institution>Oslo School of Architecture</institution>
        <title>Processing Workshop</title>
        <description>One day workshop of exercises and lectures discussing critical issues of responsive software.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Casey Reas</name>
            <email>reas@groupc.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>AHO website</title>
                <url>http://www.aho.no/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>8 February 2003</date>
        <institution>New York University ITP</institution>
        <title>Processing Workshop</title>
        <description>One day workshop focusing on communicating Processing within the context of Macromedia Director and Flash.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Joshua Nimoy</name>
            <email>josh.nimoy@verizon.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>ITP website</title>
                <url>http://itp.nyu.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>3-4 February 2003</date>
        <institution>Transmediale.03</institution>
        <title>Processing Workshop</title>
        <description>Two five hour workshops taught by Casey Reas, Boris Müller, and Hernando Barragan. Processing was used as an environment for introducing basic element of computer programming to an audience of media artists and designers.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Casey Reas</name>
            <email>reas@groupc.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Transmediale website</title>
                <url>http://www.transmediale.de/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>24 January 2003</date>
        <institution>Interaction Ivrea</institution>
        <title>Piemonte Programming Workshop</title>
        <description>Participants in this five hour workshop were introduced to the fundamentals of computer programming within the context of visual form, drawing, and responsive form. All pariticipants were beginning programmers with some prior experience with Python or Design By Numbers.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Casey Reas</name>
            <email>reas@groupc.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Workshop website</title>
                <url>http://processing.org/learning/courses/ivrea</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>7-17 January 2003</date>
        <institution>HyperWerk FHBB</institution>
        <title>Living Surfaces Part I &amp; II</title>
        <description>Participants in this two week workshop were introduced to the fundamentals of computer programming within the context of images, drawing, animation, and responsive form.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Casey Reas</name>
            <email>reas@groupc.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Workshop website for Part I</title>
                <url>http://processing.org/learning/courses/hyperwerk</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title>Part II</title>
                <url>http://processing.org/learning/courses/hyperwerk2/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Year project 2002-2003</date>
        <institution>Sint Lucas Antwerpen</institution>
        <title>Dotornot</title>
        <description>Processing is used as a tool to do fundamental research on design and the language of form. Starting from the most fundamental element of design, the dot, we try to rebuild the rules of design using pure programming.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Lucas Nijs</name>
            <email>e.media@skynet.be</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Dotornot</title>
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2002</date>
        <institution>N.Y.U Tisch School of Art</institution>
        <title>Code And Me</title>
        <description>The course helps graduate students of various backgrounds discover why and how they would use code in functional and expressive ways. Architects, Artists, Industrial Designers, Musicians, and Scientists will use Processing during the semester to establish a personal sensibility to coding.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Amit Pitaru</name>
            <email>amit@pitaru.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>ITP website</title>
                <url>http://itp.nyu.edu/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>12 November 2002</date>
        <institution>Royal Conservatory in The Hague</institution>
        <title>Interfaculty Image and Sound, Processing Workshop</title>
        <description>A one day workshop with the Interfaculty Image and Sound program at the Royal Conservatory in The Hague. Casey Reas, David Lu, Hernando Barragán, Davide Agnelli, Mathias Dahlström, Marc Escobosa, and Raphaël Meyer from Interaction Ivrea worked with a group of students to explain basic concepts of programming.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Casey Reas</name>
            <email>reas@groupc.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Interfaculty Image and Sound</title>
                <url>http://www.interfaculty.nl/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>October 2002</date>
        <institution>Interaction Ivrea</institution>
        <title>Points and Pixels</title>
        <description>A course in visual communication design for graduate students with backgrounds in engineering and humanities disciplines. Processing was used as a tool for integrating existing programming skills with emerging visual skills.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Casey Reas</name>
            <email>reas@groupc.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Course website</title>
                <url>http://courses.interaction-ivrea.it/pointsandpixels/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2002</date>
        <institution>Parsons School of Design</institution>
        <title>Java I</title>
        <description>Processing was used to introduce students to basic programming concepts and to ease them into the Java language in this introductory programming course.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Zach Lieberman</name>
            <email>zlieb@parsons.edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>22-23 April 2002</date>
        <institution>ENSCI Les Atelier</institution>
        <title>Workshop Algorithmique</title>
        <description>Twenty-six design students from ENSCI, ENCAD, and a few members of Hyptique participated in this two day Parisian workshop taught by Casey Reas, Ben Fry, and Peter Cho.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Casey Reas</name>
            <email>reas@groupc.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Workshop images</title>
                <url>http://processing.org/learning/courses/lesateliers_images.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>12-15 January 2002</date>
        <institution>HyperWerk FHBB</institution>
        <title>Interactive Image Workshop</title>
        <description>Fifteen students participated in a one week workshop taught by Casey Reas in Basel, Switzerland. Hundreds of programs were written and the spirit of Jean Tinguely was in the air.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Casey Reas</name>
            <email>reas@groupc.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Workshop images</title>
                <url>http://processing.org/learning/courses/hyperwerk_images.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Spring 2002</date>
        <institution>Parsons School of Design</institution>
        <title>Audiovisual Systems and Machines</title>
        <description>Graduate students in Golan Levin&apos;s AVSYS course at Parsons spent two weeks exploring abstract animation in Processing.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Golan Levin</name>
            <email>golan@flong.com</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Assignments</title>
                <url>http://a.parsons.edu/%7Eavsys/homework6/</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>14-16 December 2001</date>
        <institution>Interaction Design Institute Ivrea</institution>
        <title />
        <description>Over the course of two evenings, ambitious students at Interaction Ivrea took part in an exploratory Processing workshop.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Casey Reas</name>
            <email>reas@groupc.net</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
    <course>
        <date>Fall 2001</date>
        <institution>MIT Media Laboratory</institution>
        <title>Computational Media Design</title>
        <description>Processing was used as tool for exploring the intersection of the physical and virtual in MAS968, a course in computational media design taught by John Maeda, Ben Fry, and Tom White.</description>
        <contact>
            <name>Ben Fry</name>
            <email>fry@media.mit.edu</email>
        </contact>
        <links>
            <link>
                <title>Online exhibition</title>
                <url>http://acg.media.mit.edu/courses/masxxx/people.html</url>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
            <link>
                <title />
                <url />
            </link>
        </links>
    </course>
</courses>
