<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<happenings>
    <item>
        <date>Fall 2001</date>
        <description>Processing used as a tool for exploring the intersection of the physical and virtual in MAS968, a course in computational media design taught by John Maeda, Ben Fry, and Tom White at the MIT Media Laboratory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>7 December 2001</date>
        <description>Processing is presented at Sonic Acts in Amsterdam.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>14 &amp; 16 December 2001</date>
        <description>Over the course of two evenings, ambitious students at the Interaction Design Institute Ivrea took part in an exploratory Processing workshop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>12-15 January 2002</date>
        <description>Processing workshop at Hyperwerk in Basel, Switzerland. Fifteen students participated in a one week workshop taught by Casey Reas. Hundreds of programs were written and the spirit of Jean Tinguely was in the air. <a href="learning/courses/hyperwerk_images.html">Workshop images</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>Spring 2002</date>
        <description>Processing is used as a part of Golan Levin&apos;s Audiovisual Systems Course (AVES) at the Parsons School of Design in New York.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>20 April 2002</date>
        <description>Processing was presented during the Formalisation and Creativity session of Numer02 at the Center Pompidou in Paris. <a href="happenings/numer02/index.html">Transcript of presentation</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>22-23 April 2002</date>
        <description>Tweny-six students from ENSCI, ENCAD, and a few members of Hyptique participated in this two day Parisian workshop taught by Casey Reas, Ben Fry, and Peter Cho. <a href="learning/courses/lesateliers_images.html">Workshop images</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>25-27 June 2002</date>
        <description>Processing and posters exploring genomic cartography created in Processing were presented as an exhibit at the DIS2002 conference in London.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>19 August 2003</date>
        <description>Processing featured at <a href="http://www.neural.it/nnews/proce55ing.htm">Neural.it</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>Fall 2002</date>
        <description>Processing is used as a part of Zach Lieberman&apos;s Java course at the Parsons School of Design in New York.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>Fall 2002</date>
        <description>Processing is used as a part of Casey Reas&apos; <a href="http://courses.interaction-ivrea.it/pointsandpixels/">Points and Pixels</a> course at Interaction Ivrea.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>27 September 2002</date>
        <description>Processing is featured in issue 64 of De:Bug, the Zeitung fuer elektronische Lebensaspekte.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>11-12 November 2002</date>
        <description>Processing in the Netherlands. A one day workshop in the Hague at the Royal Conservatory&apos;s Image and Sound program, a lecture in the University of Leiden&apos;s Media Technology program, and an informal presentation in Erik van Blokland&apos;s class at the Royal Academy for Fine &amp; Applied Arts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>19 November 2002</date>
        <description>An intimate Processing presentation in Helsinki at the space of the artist group Amfibio.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>2 December 2002</date>
        <description>Processing in London. Processing presentation at the Bartlett School of Architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>7-17 January 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Switzerland. A two week workshop at HyperWerk FHBB. In the <a href="learning/courses/hyperwerk/">first week</a>, students executed a series of short technical exercises and in the <a href="learning/courses/hyperwerk2/">second week</a> they developed a longer exercise in the spirit of the <a href="http://www.singlecell.org">DoubleCell</a> project. On 10 January, Processing was presented in a lecture at the Bern HGKK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>3-5 February 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Berlin. Two workshops for the <a href="http://www.transmediale.de" target="new">Transmediale.03</a> on 3,4 February. Processing and its larger context presented at Automaten at 20:00 on 4 February.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>8 February 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in New York. A one day workshop at New York University&apos;s Interactive Telecommunication Program.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>9 February 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Oslo. A one day workshop with the Interaction Design program at the Oslo School of Architecture. Processing is used as a platform for discussing critical issues regarding visual aspects of responsive software.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>7 March 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Manila. A presentation at the Ateneo IT Forum, a conference and exhibition in the Philippines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>11-12 March 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in London. A presentation at Goldsmiths College, Central St. Martins, IDEO, and for the program &quot;The Aesthetics of Code&quot; at 19:00 on 12 March at the Design Council.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>11 April 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Colombia. A one day workshop in Bogot&amp;aacute; at the School of Art, Universidad de Los Andes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>11 April 2003</date>
        <description>Processing is selected for three presentation at Siggraph 2003 in San Diego: Sketches and Applications, Web Presentation, and Web Expo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>18-20 April 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Brussels. A three day workshop and presentation at <a href="http://www.imal.org/">iMAL</a> (Interactive Media Art Laboratory).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>16, 19, 23 April 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Colombia. Lectures and workshops by Hernando Barrag&amp;aacute;n at the Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, Bogot&amp;aacute;. &quot;La programaci&amp;oacute;n en medios electr&amp;oacute;nicos&quot; lecture at 2nd International Workshop Genetic Architectures. Presentation at 3rd International Workshop Contruir sobre lo construido. A one day workshop at the School of Architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>1-3 May 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Barcelona. Software written in Processing was presented by Manny Tan and James Patterson at the OFFF (Online Flash Film Festival) in Barcelona.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>3 May - 31 May 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Manila. A five week Computational Media Design workshop at Ateneo de Manila University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>13 May 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Los Angeles. &quot;Programming Media&quot; lecture by Casey Reas at 18:00 in the UCLA Design | Media Arts department.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>19 May 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Cologne. A one day workshop at the Academy of Media Arts (Kunsthochschule f&amp;uuml;r Medien K&amp;ouml;ln).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>28 May 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Nagoya. Students of Hironobu Fujiyoshi have completed their course in graphics for mobile communications and posted the work <a href="http://www.vision.cs.chubu.ac.jp/Proce55ing/Programming/" target="_new">online</a>.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>30 May 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in London. Presentations at the Architectural Association Design Research Laboratory (AADRL) and the Royal College of Art&apos;s Interaction Design program.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>27-28 June 2003</date>
        <description>
            <a href="http://www.interaction-ivrea.it" target="_new">Interaction Ivrea</a> end-of-year exhibition. A two day event featuring design research results and thesis projects from the first graduating class of Interaction Ivrea.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>6-13 July 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Seoul. Four day xD_5 Workshop at Hong-Ik University and a seminar at Artcenter Nabi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>30-31 July 2003</date>
        <description>Processing at Siggraph 2003 in San Diego. Presentations in the programs Sketches &amp; Applications, Web Graphics, and Web Expo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>11 August 2003</date>
        <description>Processing is featured on page 61 of the September 2003 edition of Wired Magazine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>28 August 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Vienna. Many Processing applications are featured in the exhibition <a href="http://www.abstraction-now.at/the-online-project/">Abstraction Now</a> at the K&amp;uuml;nstlerhaus Wein. Contributions from Lia, Manny Tan, REAS, Marius Watz, and Glen Murphy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>6-11 September 2003</date>
        <description>Processing at <a href="http://www.aec.at" target="_new">Ars Electronica</a>. Processing included in the Electrolobby and presented in the Symposium. A group of developers including Amit Pitaru, Ed Burton, Schoenerwissen, Zach Lieberman, Marius Watz, Lia, Juha Huuskonen, Ben Fry, and Casey Reas spent the week writing software and promoting the project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>01 October 2003</date>
        <description>Processing is featured in the Sept/Oct edition of Print magazine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>01 October 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Hebrew. Heidi Cropp and Ariel Malka release <a href="http://www.processing.co.il" target="_new">http://www.processing.co.il</a>.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>13 October 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Berlin. A presentation at the extraordinary <a href="http://bootlab.org/" target="_new">Bootlab</a> sponsored by the Transmediale and the Office for Computational Design.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>16 October 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Los Angeles. Presentation for Perry Hoberman&apos;s Experiments in Interactivity course at the University of Southern California (USC).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>4 November 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Cambridge. Ben visits Stephen Ervin&apos;s Programming in Java class at the Harvard Design School (GSD).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>13-14 November 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in India. Two day workshop organized by Rajesh Dahiya at the National Institute of Design in Ahmedabad.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>14 November 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in New Haven. Ben visits Simon Greenwold&apos;s <a href="http://www.architecture.yale.edu/872a/">Model Based Design</a> studio at the Yale School of Architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>5 December 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Bremen. <a href="http://www.esono.com/workshops/profile06/output.html" target="_new">Workshop</a> by Boris Muller and Hilla Neske at the Profile Intermedia 6 conference in Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>15-19 December 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Italy. Casey Reas teaches the five day <a href="http://people.interaction-ivrea.it/proce55ing/dec2003/" target="new">Programming Mobile Media</a> Workshop at Interaction Ivrea.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>15-19 December 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Seoul. Peter Cho teaches the five day <a href="http://sidi.hongik.ac.kr/xd6/peter/index.html">xD_6 Workshop</a> at Hong-Ik University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>24-26 December 2003</date>
        <description>Processing in Israel. Two and a half day workshop at the Israeli Center for Digital Art in Holon, by Ariel Malka and Heidi Horowitz of <a href="http://www.processing.co.il">Processing.co.il</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>12-16 January 2004</date>
        <description>Processing workshop in Basel. The third annual January Hyperwerk workshop. Taught by Marius Watz.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>15 January 2004</date>
        <description>We&apos;re feeling lucky. Typing &quot;Processing&quot; into Google and clicking the &quot;I&apos;m Feeling Lucky&quot; button will now take you here!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>19 February 2004</date>
        <description>Presentations for the classes of George Legrady and Marcos Novak in the Media Arts and Technology (MAT) program at University of California Santa Barbara.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>20 February 2004</date>
        <description>SIGGRAPH Manila is the visit of ACM SIGGRAPH&apos;s senior delegates exploring ideas on computer graphics and interactive techniques together with the Filipino design community. Martin Gomez will present Processing</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>24 February - 11 March 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Los Angeles. A five session Processing workshop for the USC&apos;s Interactive Media Division.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>4 March 2004</date>
        <description>Processing lecture at San Francisco Art Institute and presentation for Krister Olsson&apos;s course. We also had the pleasure of meeting Joshua Kit Clayton of Cycling&apos;74, author of <a href="http://www.cycling74.com/products/jitter.html">Jitter</a>.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>19 March 2004</date>
        <description>Cinema Redux featured in the <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/arts/fridayreview/story/0,12102,1172523,00.html">Guardian</a> newspaper.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>22 March 2004</date>
        <description>Processing presentation for Peter Lunenfeld&apos;s Design Dialogues course at Art Center College of Design, in Pasedena California.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>31 March - 3 April 2004</date>
        <description>Processing workshop at University of Huddersfield, UK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>2 April 2004</date>
        <description>Screenshots from various Processing work featured in an interview with Brendan Dawes in MacUser.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>3,4 April 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Istanbul. Reed Kram teaches at workshop at Istanbul Bilgi University&apos;s VCD department.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>4 April 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Toronto. Session at Flash in the Can, entitled Interactive Design and the Outside World featuring various Processing projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>6-8 April 2004</date>
        <description>Processing Lecture and workshop at PixelRaiders 2 Conference at Sheffield Hallam University, UK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>13-16 April 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Turku, Finland. Juha Huuskonen gives a workshop at the Turku Arts Academy Digital Arts program.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>16 April 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Toronto. <a href="http://www.flux.to/">Flux re:creation</a> featuring Brendan Dawes&apos; work with Processing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>19-23 April 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Stockholm. Juha Huuskonen gives a workshop at the Royal University College of Fine Arts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>4-9 May 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Latvia. Marius Watz presents Processing at the <a href="http://www.rixc.lv/ram/">RAM5</a>, Open Source Media Architecture event in Riga.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>13-14 May 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Slovenia. Marius Watz gives the workshop &quot;Processing 101 - a tool for computational design&quot; during the <a href="http://www.magdalena.org/">Magdalena</a> festival in Maribor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>17-19 June 2004</date>
        <description>Processing at Sonar, Barcelona. A selection of Processing work, curated by Jos&amp;eacute; Luis de Vicente will be presented at Barcelona&apos;s Museum of Contemporary Arts (MACBA).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>14 July - 31 July</date>
        <description>
            <a href="http://www.ntticc.or.jp/Schedule/2004/reactivecreative/index.html" target="_new">ICC NewSchool 9 Reactive/Creative</a> in Tokyo is featuring a Processing workshop by Tetsu Kondo and Amit Pitaru.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>8 August 2004</date>
        <description>Processing is presented at the <a href="http://www.c-level.cc/classes/hackerclub.html">Los Angeles Art and Technology Hackers Club</a> at <a href="http://www.c-level.cc/">C-Level</a>.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>11 August 2004</date>
        <description>Processing is presented during the Visualization Session of the <a href="http://www.siggraph.org/s2004/conference/web/index.php?pageID=conference">Web Graphics</a> session at <a href="http://www.siggraph.org/s2004/">Siggraph 2004</a>.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>25-27 August 2004</date>
        <description>Who owns our (software) culture? A panel at <a href="http://www.isea2004.net/">ISEA 2004</a> with Miller Puckette, creator of MAX and PD, and Casey Reas, co-founder of Processing. Moderated by Juha Huuskonen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>25-27 August 2004</date>
        <description>Processing is presented at the <a href="http://readme.runme.org/camp.php">Dorkbot City Camp</a> in Aarhus Denmark.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>4 September 2004</date>
        <description>Processing is featured on the Danish radio program <a href="http://www.dr.dk/Videnskab/Harddisken/Programmer/2004/09/readme2.htm">Harddisken</a>. Interview by Thomas Birch and Thomas Markussen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>23 September 2004</date>
        <description>Processing is featured at <a href="http://www.interact1.co.uk/">Interact1</a> in London.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>28 October 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Milan. Audio seminar by Raffaele de Tintis at Domus Academy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>27-29 October 2004</date>
        <description>Processing at Fabrica. A three day Processing workshop on computer vision by Golan Levin at Fabrica in Treviso, Italy. Thank you Andy!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>2 November 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Hong Kong. Workshop by Casey Reas at the City University of Hong Kong in association with the Microwave International Media Art Festival. Thank you Fion!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>13 November 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Milan. Audio seminar by Raffaele de Tintis at Reload.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>12, 13 November 2004</date>
        <description>Processing in Minneapolis. Processing lecture and workshop at MCAD (Minneapolis College of Art + Design) by Casey Reas and Ben Fry. Thank you Piotr and Santiago!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>11 January 2005</date>
        <description>Processing wins the 2005 <a href="http://www.tdctokyo.org/index_e.html" target="_new">Tokyo TDC</a> Interactive Design Prize.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>1-3 April 2005</date>
        <description>Ben Fry and Casey Reas present Processing for the Tokyo TDC.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>9-11 April 2005</date>
        <description>Ben Fry, Casey Reas, Robert Hodgin, Jared Tarbell present at <a href="http://www.fitc.ca/" target="_new">FITC</a>, Toronto.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>17 April 2005</date>
        <description>
            <a href="http://machineproject.com/classes/processing/casey_reas_talk.php" target="_new">Processing presention</a> at the Machine Project in Echo Park, Los Angeles. Thanks Mark!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>11 May 2005</date>
        <description>Processing in San Diego. Presentation for Lev Manovich&apos;s Current Issues in Digital Art course at the University of California San Diego.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>12-14 May 2005</date>
        <description>OFFF in Barcelona features presentations by Amit Pitaru, Jared Tarbell, and Ed Burton. <a href="http://www.offf.ws/index.php?lang=en" target="_new">More info</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>16-18 June 2005</date>
        <description>Sonar 2005 in Barcelona! Processing presentation in Sonarama, Processing live visuals for 2 Many DJs, Tree installation by Texone, and more...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>20-23 June 2005</date>
        <description>Making Things Move workshop by Zachary Lieberman at the MediaLabMadrid. Taught with Processing. <a href="http://processing.org/discourse/yabb_beta/YaBB.cgi?board=Events;action=display;num=1118597907" target="_new">More info</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>22 June 2005</date>
        <description>Real Time Everything symposium at Watershed Media Centre, Bristol. Processing presented by Yasser Rashid. <a href="http://processing.org/discourse/yabb_beta/YaBB.cgi?board=Events;action=display;num=1119293192" target="_new">More info</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>27 June - 1 August 2005</date>
        <description>John Maeda has organized the <a href="http://www.aiga.org/content.cfm/didcamp" target="_new">Digital Information Design Camp</a> for Summer 2005. Instructors include Ben Fry, Golan Levin, Peter Cho, Martin Wattenberg, Lisa Strausfeld, and Ellen Lupton. Application forms are available online.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>1,2 July 2005</date>
        <description>UCL Adaptive Architecture and Computation Open Day. Processing works on display at Bartlett&apos;s Adaptive Architecture Lab.  <a href="http://processing.org/discourse/yabb_beta/YaBB.cgi?board=Events;action=display;num=1119011942" target="_new">More info</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>23,24 September 2005</date>
        <description>Generator.x conference at Atelier Nord, Oslo. Organized by Marius Watz, who states, &quot;If you ever wanted an excuse to visit Norway, this might be the time...&quot; <a href="http://processing.org/discourse/yabb_beta/YaBB.cgi?board=Events;action=display;num=1118890876" target="_new">More info</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <date>11 January 05</date>
        <description>I posted something to the site.</description>
    </item>
</happenings>
