<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<happenings>
    <item>
        <startdate>9 April 2005</startdate>
        <enddate>11 April 2005</enddate>
        <description>Ben Fry, Casey Reas, Robert Hodgin, Jared Tarbell present at <a href="http://www.fitc.ca/">FITC</a>, Toronto.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>17 April 2005</startdate>
        <enddate />
        <description>
            <a href="http://machineproject.com/classes/processing/casey_reas_talk.php">Processing presention</a> at the Machine Project in Echo Park, Los Angeles. Thanks Mark!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>11 May 2005</startdate>
        <enddate />
        <description>Processing in San Diego. Presentation for Lev Manovich&apos;s Current Issues in Digital Art course at the University of California San Diego.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>12 May 2005</startdate>
        <enddate>14 May 2005</enddate>
        <description>OFFF in Barcelona features presentations by Amit Pitaru, Jared Tarbell, and Ed Burton. <a href="http://www.offf.ws/index.php?lang=en">More info</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>30 May 2005</startdate>
        <enddate />
        <description>Processing receives the Golden Nica for Net Vision at the 2005 Prix Ars Electronica, the International Competition for CyberArts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>16 June 2005</startdate>
        <enddate>18 June 2005</enddate>
        <description>Sonar 2005 in Barcelona! Processing presentation in Sonarama, Processing live visuals for 2 Many DJs, Tree installation by Texone, and more...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>20 June 2005</startdate>
        <enddate>23 June 2005</enddate>
        <description>Making Things Move workshop by Zachary Lieberman at the MediaLabMadrid. Taught with Processing. <a href="http://processing.org/discourse/yabb_beta/YaBB.cgi?board=Events;action=display;num=1118597907">More info</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>22 June 2005</startdate>
        <enddate />
        <description>Real Time Everything symposium at Watershed Media Centre, Bristol. Processing presented by Yasser Rashid. <a href="http://processing.org/discourse/yabb_beta/YaBB.cgi?board=Events;action=display;num=1119293192" target="_new">More info</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>June 27 2005</startdate>
        <enddate>1 August 2005</enddate>
        <description>John Maeda has organized the <a href="http://www.aiga.org/content.cfm/didcamp">Digital Information Design Camp</a> for Summer 2005. Instructors include Ben Fry, Golan Levin, Peter Cho, Martin Wattenberg, Lisa Strausfeld, and Ellen Lupton. Application forms are available online.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>1 July 2005</startdate>
        <enddate>2 July 2005</enddate>
        <description>UCL Adaptive Architecture and Computation Open Day. Processing works on display at Bartlett&apos;s Adaptive Architecture Lab. <a href="http://processing.org/discourse/yabb_beta/YaBB.cgi?board=Events;action=display;num=1119011942">More info</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>6 July 2005</startdate>
        <enddate />
        <description>Processing workshops presented at Flash Forward 2005 in New York. An Introduction to Processing from Amit Pitaru and and discussion of Physical Interaction Design Using Processing from Tom Igoe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>6 July 2005</startdate>
        <enddate>8 July 2005</enddate>
        <description>Screen Paper Pattern, a Processing workshop at Fabrica (Treviso, Italy) focusing on writing code for generating printed patterns. Thanks Andy!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>15 July 2005</startdate>
        <enddate />
        <description>Processing workshop by Federico Joselevich at CopyFight in Barcelona! <a href="http://www.elastico.net/copyfight/">More info</a>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>3 August 2005</startdate>
        <enddate />
        <description>Processing is presented in the Web Program at <a href="http://www.siggraph.org/s2005/main.php?f=conference&amp;p=web&amp;s=application&amp;PHPSESSID=100d40e8535fdd7d5157a2c4fac1683e#processing">Siggraph 2005</a> in Los Angeles. Catch us at the beach the next day!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>4 August 2005</startdate>
        <enddate />
        <description>Katya Moorman presents Processing at the legendary Black Mountain college in Asheville, North Carolina.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>1 September 2005</startdate>
        <enddate>6 September 2005</enddate>
        <description>Processing receives the Golden Nica award at the Ars Electronica Gala in Linz, Austria on 2 September. The project is presented at the Prix Ars Electronica Forum at 10:30 on 5 September.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <startdate>23 September 2005</startdate>
        <enddate>24 September 2005</enddate>
        <description>Generator.x conference at Atelier Nord, Oslo. Organized by Marius Watz, who states, &quot;If you ever wanted an excuse to visit Norway, this might be the time...&quot; <a href="http://processing.org/discourse/yabb_beta/YaBB.cgi?board=Events;action=display;num=1118890876">More info</a>
        </description>
    </item>
</happenings>
